<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz>
    <question>
        <text>How do high-altitude organisms adapt their energy metabolism?</text>
        <option>They stop using oxygen</option>
        <option>They enhance oxygen utilization efficiency</option>
        <option>They only use fermentation</option>
        <option>They reduce all metabolism</option>
        <answer>They enhance oxygen utilization efficiency</answer>
        <explanation>High-altitude organisms adapt to low oxygen conditions by enhancing oxygen transport, increasing mitochondrial density, and modifying metabolic pathways to improve oxygen utilization efficiency.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>What metabolic adaptations occur in high-altitude plants?</text>
        <option>They stop photosynthesis</option>
        <option>They modify photosynthetic and respiratory pathways</option>
        <option>They only use CAM photosynthesis</option>
        <option>They increase water use</option>
        <answer>They modify photosynthetic and respiratory pathways</answer>
        <explanation>High-altitude plants adapt by modifying both photosynthetic and respiratory pathways to function efficiently under low CO2 partial pressure and intense UV radiation while maintaining energy balance.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>How do animals maintain ATP production at high altitudes?</text>
        <option>They only use anaerobic metabolism</option>
        <option>They increase metabolic efficiency and oxygen delivery</option>
        <option>They reduce energy needs</option>
        <option>They use photosynthesis</option>
        <answer>They increase metabolic efficiency and oxygen delivery</answer>
        <explanation>Animals at high altitudes maintain ATP production through increased hemoglobin oxygen affinity, enhanced capillary density, and improved metabolic efficiency in using limited oxygen.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>What role does mitochondrial density play in altitude adaptation?</text>
        <option>It decreases at high altitudes</option>
        <option>It increases to improve oxygen utilization</option>
        <option>It remains unchanged</option>
        <option>It has no effect on adaptation</option>
        <answer>It increases to improve oxygen utilization</answer>
        <explanation>Increased mitochondrial density in high-altitude organisms improves oxygen utilization efficiency by providing more sites for aerobic respiration and energy production under low oxygen conditions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>How do high-altitude adaptations affect energy efficiency?</text>
        <option>They reduce efficiency</option>
        <option>They improve overall energy efficiency</option>
        <option>They have no effect</option>
        <option>They only affect growth</option>
        <answer>They improve overall energy efficiency</answer>
        <explanation>High-altitude adaptations typically improve overall energy efficiency through enhanced oxygen utilization, modified metabolic pathways, and optimized energy allocation for survival in challenging conditions.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>