<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz><question number="1">
        <prompt>A country's GDP will be greater than its GNP when:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Net factor payments from abroad are positive</option>
            <option letter="b">Net factor payments from abroad are negative</option>
            <option letter="c">Exports exceed imports</option>
            <option letter="d">The trade balance is zero</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>GDP exceeds GNP when payments to foreign factors of production exceed payments received from domestic factors operating abroad (negative net factor payments).</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="2">
        <prompt>The Phillips Curve shows the relationship between:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Unemployment and economic growth</option>
            <option letter="b">Inflation and economic growth</option>
            <option letter="c">Unemployment and inflation</option>
            <option letter="d">Inflation and interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The Phillips Curve illustrates the inverse relationship between unemployment and inflation rates in the short run.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="3">
        <prompt>Which would most likely flatten the AD curve?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in the interest elasticity of investment</option>
            <option letter="b">A decrease in the interest elasticity of investment</option>
            <option letter="c">An increase in the money supply</option>
            <option letter="d">A decrease in government spending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When investment spending becomes less sensitive to interest rates, the AD curve becomes steeper. Conversely, greater interest sensitivity would make it flatter.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="4">
        <prompt>The loanable funds market equilibrium determines:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The exchange rate</option>
            <option letter="b">The real interest rate</option>
            <option letter="c">The money supply</option>
            <option letter="d">The price level</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The intersection of saving and investment in the loanable funds market determines the real interest rate that balances saving and investment.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="5">
        <prompt>Which of the following would shift the LRAS curve to the right?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in the money supply</option>
            <option letter="b">A decrease in income tax rates</option>
            <option letter="c">An improvement in technology</option>
            <option letter="d">An increase in consumer confidence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Technological improvement increases the economy's productive capacity, shifting the long-run aggregate supply curve to the right as more output can be produced at any price level.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="6">
        <prompt>Crowding out occurs when:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Government spending decreases private investment</option>
            <option letter="b">Imports exceed exports</option>
            <option letter="c">Tax revenues exceed government spending</option>
            <option letter="d">The money supply decreases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Crowding out occurs when increased government spending raises interest rates, reducing private investment as borrowing becomes more expensive.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="7">
        <prompt>Which policy combination would most likely result in higher real GDP with stable prices?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Expansionary fiscal policy and contractionary monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="b">Contractionary fiscal policy and expansionary monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="c">Expansionary supply-side policy and contractionary demand policy</option>
            <option letter="d">Expansionary supply-side policy and expansionary demand policy</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Expanding aggregate supply while controlling aggregate demand can increase output while maintaining price stability.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="8">
        <prompt>A decrease in the federal funds rate would most directly affect:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The money multiplier</option>
            <option letter="b">Bank lending</option>
            <option letter="c">The reserve requirement</option>
            <option letter="d">Government spending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>A lower federal funds rate directly affects bank lending by reducing the cost of borrowing between banks, making it easier for banks to lend to customers.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="9">
        <prompt>In the long-run aggregate supply curve (LRAS), an increase in labor productivity would:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Shift LRAS left</option>
            <option letter="b">Shift LRAS right</option>
            <option letter="c">Move along the existing LRAS curve</option>
            <option letter="d">Have no effect on LRAS</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>An increase in labor productivity represents an improvement in productive capacity, shifting the long-run aggregate supply curve rightward as the economy can produce more output at any price level.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="10">
        <prompt>Which of the following would NOT cause a shift in the aggregate demand (AD) curve?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A change in consumer confidence</option>
            <option letter="b">A change in government spending</option>
            <option letter="c">A change in the price level</option>
            <option letter="d">A change in interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>A change in the price level causes movement along the existing AD curve, not a shift. The other factors are determinants that would shift the entire AD curve.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="11">
        <prompt>The short-run aggregate supply (SRAS) curve is upward sloping because:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Prices and wages are sticky in the short run</option>
            <option letter="b">Resources are fully employed</option>
            <option letter="c">The money supply determines output</option>
            <option letter="d">Consumer spending increases with income</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The SRAS curve slopes upward because prices and wages are sticky (inflexible) in the short run, meaning firms will produce more when prices rise while costs remain relatively constant.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="12">
        <prompt>At the full-employment level of output:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">There is no unemployment</option>
            <option letter="b">Only structural unemployment exists</option>
            <option letter="c">The natural rate of unemployment exists</option>
            <option letter="d">Cyclical unemployment is positive</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>At full employment, the economy operates at potential GDP with the natural rate of unemployment, which includes frictional and structural but not cyclical unemployment.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="13">
        <prompt>What happens to the price level and real GDP in the short run when both AD and SRAS decrease?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Price level falls, real GDP falls</option>
            <option letter="b">Price level falls, real GDP rises</option>
            <option letter="c">Price level rises, real GDP falls</option>
            <option letter="d">Price level rises, real GDP rises</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>When both AD and SRAS decrease, both the price level and real GDP fall, as both curves shift left, creating a new equilibrium at lower price and output levels.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="14">
        <prompt>The interest rate effect explains why:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The AD curve slopes upward</option>
            <option letter="b">The AD curve slopes downward</option>
            <option letter="c">The SRAS curve slopes upward</option>
            <option letter="d">The LRAS curve is vertical</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The interest rate effect helps explain the negative slope of the AD curve: higher prices increase money demand, raising interest rates and reducing investment spending.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="15">
        <prompt>A decrease in the value of a nation's currency is most likely to:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Reduce aggregate demand through lower net exports</option>
            <option letter="b">Increase aggregate demand through higher net exports</option>
            <option letter="c">Reduce aggregate supply through higher import costs</option>
            <option letter="d">Both B and C</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>Currency depreciation increases net exports (shifting AD right) but also raises import costs (shifting SRAS left), affecting both aggregate demand and supply.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="16">
        <prompt>The slope of the aggregate supply curve becomes more vertical as:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The economy approaches full employment</option>
            <option letter="b">Unemployment increases</option>
            <option letter="c">Prices become more flexible</option>
            <option letter="d">Wages become more rigid</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>As the economy approaches full employment, additional increases in aggregate demand lead to smaller increases in output and larger increases in prices, making AS more vertical.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="17">
        <prompt>The multiplier effect is smaller when:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The MPC is larger</option>
            <option letter="b">The tax rate is lower</option>
            <option letter="c">Imports are higher</option>
            <option letter="d">Government spending increases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Higher imports create more leakages from the circular flow of income, reducing the multiplier effect as more spending flows out of the domestic economy.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="18">
        <prompt>Which of the following would increase velocity in the equation of exchange?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in the money supply</option>
            <option letter="b">A decrease in nominal GDP</option>
            <option letter="c">Financial innovation reducing cash holdings</option>
            <option letter="d">An increase in bank reserves</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Financial innovations that reduce the need to hold cash increase the velocity of money as each dollar is used more frequently in transactions.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="19">
        <prompt>In the long run, an increase in the money supply will:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increase real GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">Decrease real GDP</option>
            <option letter="c">Increase only the price level</option>
            <option letter="d">Decrease only the price level</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>According to the classical dichotomy, in the long run, changes in the money supply affect only nominal variables (like prices) and not real variables (like GDP).</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="20">
        <prompt>Which fiscal policy action would have the largest multiplier effect?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">A decrease in income taxes</option>
            <option letter="c">An increase in transfer payments</option>
            <option letter="d">A decrease in corporate taxes</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Government spending has the largest multiplier effect because it directly adds to aggregate demand, while tax changes and transfers work through changes in disposable income.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="21">
        <prompt>The Lucas Critique suggests that economic policy evaluations should:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Focus only on historical relationships</option>
            <option letter="b">Consider how expectations change behavior</option>
            <option letter="c">Ignore international factors</option>
            <option letter="d">Rely solely on monetary aggregates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The Lucas Critique argues that policy evaluations must account for how people's expectations and behavior change in response to policy changes, rather than relying solely on historical relationships.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="22">
        <prompt>The sterilization of foreign exchange interventions involves:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Allowing the money supply to change</option>
            <option letter="b">Offsetting changes in the money supply</option>
            <option letter="c">Fixing exchange rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Eliminating capital controls</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Sterilization occurs when central banks offset the effects of foreign exchange interventions on the domestic money supply through offsetting open market operations.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="23">
        <prompt>According to the monetary approach to exchange rates, a higher interest rate will:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Always cause the currency to appreciate</option>
            <option letter="b">Always cause the currency to depreciate</option>
            <option letter="c">Cause appreciation only if due to monetary contraction</option>
            <option letter="d">Have no effect on exchange rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The monetary approach suggests that higher interest rates cause currency appreciation only if they result from monetary contraction rather than higher expected inflation.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="24">
        <prompt>The Tobin tax was proposed to:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Reduce income inequality</option>
            <option letter="b">Decrease currency speculation</option>
            <option letter="c">Increase government revenue</option>
            <option letter="d">Promote international trade</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The Tobin tax was proposed as a small tax on foreign exchange transactions to reduce short-term currency speculation and market volatility.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="25">
        <prompt>The real balance effect explains why:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Higher prices increase aggregate demand</option>
            <option letter="b">Lower prices increase aggregate demand</option>
            <option letter="c">Higher prices increase aggregate supply</option>
            <option letter="d">Lower prices decrease aggregate demand</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The real balance effect states that lower prices increase the real value of money holdings, making people wealthier in real terms and increasing aggregate demand.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="26">
        <prompt>In an open economy, the size of the fiscal multiplier is reduced by:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A lower marginal propensity to import</option>
            <option letter="b">A higher marginal propensity to save</option>
            <option letter="c">Lower tax rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Higher government spending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>A higher marginal propensity to save creates a larger leakage from the circular flow of income, reducing the fiscal multiplier's impact on national income.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="27">
        <prompt>Hysteresis in unemployment suggests that:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Cyclical unemployment becomes structural</option>
            <option letter="b">Unemployment is always temporary</option>
            <option letter="c">The natural rate is constant</option>
            <option letter="d">Inflation reduces unemployment</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Hysteresis occurs when temporary cyclical unemployment becomes permanent structural unemployment as workers lose skills and become detached from the labor force.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="28">
        <prompt>The impossible trinity suggests that a country cannot simultaneously have:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Low inflation, high employment, and economic growth</option>
            <option letter="b">Fixed exchange rates, independent monetary policy, and free capital flows</option>
            <option letter="c">Balanced trade, full employment, and price stability</option>
            <option letter="d">High savings, high investment, and low interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The impossible trinity (trilemma) states that a country cannot simultaneously maintain fixed exchange rates, independent monetary policy, and free capital movement.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="29">
        <prompt>If the economy is operating at potential GDP, an increase in AD will result in:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Higher output and stable prices</option>
            <option letter="b">Higher output and higher prices</option>
            <option letter="c">Stable output and higher prices</option>
            <option letter="d">Lower output and higher prices</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>At potential GDP, an increase in AD will primarily affect prices rather than output because the economy is already at its full-employment level.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="30">
        <prompt>The accelerator principle suggests that:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Investment increases when consumption decreases</option>
            <option letter="b">Investment increases more than proportionally to increases in consumer demand</option>
            <option letter="c">Prices rise faster than wages</option>
            <option letter="d">Money supply grows faster than real GDP</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The accelerator principle states that investment spending tends to increase by a larger percentage than increases in consumer demand.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="31">
        <prompt>Which would most likely result from a decrease in net capital inflows?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Appreciation of the domestic currency</option>
            <option letter="b">Decrease in domestic interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">Depreciation of the domestic currency</option>
            <option letter="d">Increase in the trade surplus</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Decreased capital inflows reduce demand for domestic currency in foreign exchange markets, causing the domestic currency to depreciate.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="32">
        <prompt>The wealth effect suggests that when the price level falls:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Real wealth increases and consumption rises</option>
            <option letter="b">Real wealth decreases and consumption falls</option>
            <option letter="c">Real wealth increases and consumption falls</option>
            <option letter="d">Real wealth remains constant and consumption rises</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>When the price level falls, the real value of money and financial assets increases, making people wealthier in real terms and increasing consumption.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="33">
        <prompt>In the equation of exchange (MV = PY), if M increases by 5% and V remains constant, what happens to nominal GDP (PY)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Decreases by 5%</option>
            <option letter="b">Increases by 5%</option>
            <option letter="c">Remains unchanged</option>
            <option letter="d">Cannot be determined without more information</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>According to the equation of exchange, if M increases by 5% and V is constant, then PY (nominal GDP) must increase by 5% to maintain the equation's equality.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="34">
        <prompt>Which policy would most effectively reduce a trade deficit?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increasing government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">Decreasing domestic saving</option>
            <option letter="c">Increasing domestic saving</option>
            <option letter="d">Decreasing interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Increasing domestic saving reduces domestic consumption, including consumption of imports, and provides more funds for investment, helping to reduce the trade deficit.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="35">
        <prompt>Which factor would NOT shift the short-run Phillips Curve?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Changes in expected inflation</option>
            <option letter="b">Supply shocks</option>
            <option letter="c">Changes in the actual unemployment rate</option>
            <option letter="d">Changes in worker productivity</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Changes in the actual unemployment rate represent movement along the Phillips Curve, not a shift. The other factors would cause the curve to shift.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="36">
        <prompt>Real interest rates will rise when:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Nominal interest rates fall faster than inflation</option>
            <option letter="b">Nominal interest rates rise faster than inflation</option>
            <option letter="c">Inflation rises faster than nominal interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Both inflation and nominal rates remain constant</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Real interest rates increase when nominal interest rates increase by more than the inflation rate, as the real rate is the nominal rate minus inflation.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="37">
        <prompt>The natural rate hypothesis implies that:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Unemployment can be permanently reduced through monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="b">There is no long-run tradeoff between inflation and unemployment</option>
            <option letter="c">Inflation and unemployment are positively correlated</option>
            <option letter="d">The Phillips Curve is stable in the long run</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The natural rate hypothesis states that there is no long-run tradeoff between inflation and unemployment; the economy returns to its natural rate regardless of the inflation rate.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="38">
        <prompt>The monetarist transmission mechanism emphasizes the:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Interest rate effects on investment</option>
            <option letter="b">Direct effects of money on spending</option>
            <option letter="c">Exchange rate channel</option>
            <option letter="d">Bank lending channel</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Monetarists emphasize the direct effect of changes in the money supply on spending, rather than indirect effects through interest rates or credit channels.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="39">
        <prompt>If the MPC is 0.8 and government spending increases by $100 billion, the change in equilibrium GDP with no crowding out would be:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$100 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">$400 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$500 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$800 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.8, the multiplier is 1/(1-0.8) = 5, so a $100 billion increase in government spending increases GDP by $500 billion without crowding out.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="40">
        <prompt>The dynamic aggregate supply curve slopes upward because:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Prices adjust faster than wages</option>
            <option letter="b">Expected inflation affects price setting</option>
            <option letter="c">Money is neutral in the long run</option>
            <option letter="d">The Phillips Curve is vertical</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The dynamic AS curve slopes upward because price setters incorporate expected inflation into their decisions, creating a relationship between inflation and output.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="41">
        <prompt>Under a system of fractional reserve banking, the money multiplier is reduced when:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Banks reduce their excess reserves</option>
            <option letter="b">The required reserve ratio decreases</option>
            <option letter="c">The public holds less currency relative to deposits</option>
            <option letter="d">The currency drain ratio increases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>An increase in the currency drain ratio (the ratio of currency to deposits held by the public) reduces the money multiplier by decreasing the amount of deposits available for lending.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="42">
        <prompt>Time inconsistency in monetary policy refers to:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The lag between policy changes and their effects</option>
            <option letter="b">The tendency to deviate from announced low-inflation policies</option>
            <option letter="c">Changes in the velocity of money</option>
            <option letter="d">Seasonal adjustments in the money supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Time inconsistency occurs when policymakers have an incentive to deviate from previously announced low-inflation policies once expectations are set.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="43">
        <prompt>The twin deficits hypothesis suggests that:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Budget deficits cause trade deficits</option>
            <option letter="b">Trade deficits cause budget deficits</option>
            <option letter="c">Both deficits are caused by high interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">The deficits are unrelated</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The twin deficits hypothesis argues that government budget deficits lead to trade deficits by increasing national borrowing and attracting foreign capital inflows.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="44">
        <prompt>In the efficiency wage theory, unemployment results from:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Minimum wage laws</option>
            <option letter="b">Firms paying above-market wages</option>
            <option letter="c">Labor unions</option>
            <option letter="d">Cyclical factors</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Efficiency wage theory suggests firms deliberately pay above-market wages to increase productivity and reduce turnover, resulting in unemployment as wages remain above market-clearing levels.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="45">
        <prompt>When the Fed conducts contractionary monetary policy, what happens to bond prices?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Rise due to lower interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">Fall due to higher interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">Remain unchanged</option>
            <option letter="d">Cannot be determined</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Contractionary monetary policy raises interest rates, causing bond prices to fall because bond prices and interest rates are inversely related.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="46">
        <prompt>The long-run aggregate supply curve is vertical because:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Prices are sticky</option>
            <option letter="b">Wages are flexible</option>
            <option letter="c">Output is determined by factor inputs and technology</option>
            <option letter="d">The money supply is constant</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>LRAS is vertical because long-run output is determined by the economy's productive capacity (labor, capital, and technology), not the price level.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="47">
        <prompt>An increase in government spending financed by borrowing will:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Decrease interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">Increase private investment</option>
            <option letter="c">Increase interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Have no effect on interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Government borrowing increases demand for loanable funds, pushing up interest rates and potentially crowding out private investment.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="48">
        <prompt>The real exchange rate appreciates when:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Domestic inflation is higher than foreign inflation</option>
            <option letter="b">Domestic inflation is lower than foreign inflation</option>
            <option letter="c">The nominal exchange rate depreciates</option>
            <option letter="d">The trade deficit increases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The real exchange rate appreciates when domestic inflation is lower than foreign inflation, making domestic goods relatively less expensive.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="49">
        <prompt>Which of the following would most likely result in cost-push inflation?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in consumer spending</option>
            <option letter="b">An increase in government spending</option>
            <option letter="c">An increase in raw material prices</option>
            <option letter="d">A decrease in interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Cost-push inflation occurs when production costs rise, such as through higher raw material prices, shifting the SRAS curve left and pushing up the price level.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="50">
        <prompt>In a fixed exchange rate system, if a country's currency is under pressure to appreciate, its central bank must:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Sell domestic currency and buy foreign currency</option>
            <option letter="b">Buy domestic currency and sell foreign currency</option>
            <option letter="c">Increase interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Decrease interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>To prevent appreciation under a fixed exchange rate, the central bank must increase the supply of domestic currency by selling it and buying foreign currency.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="51">
        <prompt>The rationale for expansionary fiscal policy during a recession is that:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Government spending crowds out private investment</option>
            <option letter="b">Tax cuts increase aggregate supply</option>
            <option letter="c">Government spending replaces lost private spending</option>
            <option letter="d">Budget deficits reduce inflation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>During recessions, government spending can help maintain aggregate demand by replacing the decline in private sector spending, helping to stabilize the economy.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="52">
        <prompt>If MPS = 0.25, what is the value of the spending multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">1.33</option>
            <option letter="b">2.50</option>
            <option letter="c">4.00</option>
            <option letter="d">0.25</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The spending multiplier equals 1/(1-MPC) or 1/MPS. With MPS = 0.25, the multiplier is 1/0.25 = 4.00.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="53">
        <prompt>According to Okun's Law, a 1% increase in unemployment above the natural rate leads to approximately:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A 1% decrease in real GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">A 2% decrease in real GDP</option>
            <option letter="c">A 3% decrease in real GDP</option>
            <option letter="d">A 4% decrease in real GDP</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Okun's Law states that for every 1 percentage point increase in unemployment above the natural rate, real GDP falls by approximately 2 percent below potential GDP.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="54">
        <prompt>The Monetary Base consists of:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Currency in circulation plus bank deposits</option>
            <option letter="b">Currency in circulation plus bank reserves</option>
            <option letter="c">Total deposits plus required reserves</option>
            <option letter="d">Total reserves plus excess reserves</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The Monetary Base (high-powered money) consists of currency in circulation plus bank reserves (both required and excess reserves).</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="55">
        <prompt>In a floating exchange rate system, a trade surplus will cause:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The domestic currency to appreciate</option>
            <option letter="b">The domestic currency to depreciate</option>
            <option letter="c">Interest rates to rise</option>
            <option letter="d">The money supply to decrease</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>A trade surplus increases foreign demand for domestic currency to pay for exports, causing the domestic currency to appreciate in a floating exchange rate system.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="56">
        <prompt>Which of the following would increase aggregate supply in both the short run and long run?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in the money supply</option>
            <option letter="b">An improvement in technology</option>
            <option letter="c">A decrease in taxes</option>
            <option letter="d">An increase in government spending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Technological improvement increases productivity and productive capacity, shifting both the short-run and long-run aggregate supply curves to the right.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="57">
        <prompt>In the long run, an economy operating above potential GDP will experience:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increasing price levels only</option>
            <option letter="b">Decreasing output only</option>
            <option letter="c">Both increasing prices and decreasing output</option>
            <option letter="d">Neither increasing prices nor decreasing output</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Above potential GDP, upward pressure on wages and prices will eventually reduce output back to potential GDP level, resulting in both higher prices and lower output.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="58">
        <prompt>The J-curve effect suggests that following currency depreciation:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The trade balance immediately improves</option>
            <option letter="b">The trade balance initially worsens before improving</option>
            <option letter="c">The trade balance continuously worsens</option>
            <option letter="d">The trade balance remains unchanged</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The J-curve shows that after currency depreciation, the trade balance initially worsens due to sticky prices and contracts, before improving as quantities adjust.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="59">
        <prompt>When the Fed engages in quantitative easing, it:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Raises the federal funds rate</option>
            <option letter="b">Purchases long-term government securities</option>
            <option letter="c">Increases the required reserve ratio</option>
            <option letter="d">Reduces the money supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Quantitative easing involves the Federal Reserve purchasing long-term government securities to lower long-term interest rates and increase the money supply.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="60">
        <prompt>A decrease in business taxes would most directly affect:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Short-run aggregate supply</option>
            <option letter="b">Long-run aggregate supply</option>
            <option letter="c">Aggregate demand</option>
            <option letter="d">Both SRAS and AD</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>Lower business taxes increase both aggregate supply (by reducing costs) and aggregate demand (by increasing business investment spending).</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="61">
        <prompt>Rational expectations theory suggests that government policies are less effective because:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">People don't understand economic policy</option>
            <option letter="b">People anticipate policy effects and adjust behavior</option>
            <option letter="c">Government policies are unpredictable</option>
            <option letter="d">Markets are inefficient</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Rational expectations theory argues that people anticipate the effects of economic policies and adjust their behavior accordingly, reducing policy effectiveness.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="62">
        <prompt>The Ricardian equivalence theorem suggests that deficit spending:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Always stimulates the economy</option>
            <option letter="b">May not stimulate the economy due to increased private saving</option>
            <option letter="c">Increases interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Decreases aggregate supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Ricardian equivalence suggests people may save more in response to government deficits, anticipating future tax increases, thus offsetting the stimulative effect.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="63">
        <prompt>In the Mundell-Fleming model with perfect capital mobility and flexible exchange rates, monetary policy is:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Completely ineffective</option>
            <option letter="b">Highly effective</option>
            <option letter="c">Only effective if coordinated internationally</option>
            <option letter="d">Only effective in the long run</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With flexible exchange rates and perfect capital mobility, monetary policy is highly effective because exchange rate changes amplify its impact on aggregate demand.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="64">
        <prompt>Cost-push inflation is most likely to be accompanied by:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Rising real GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">Falling unemployment</option>
            <option letter="c">Rising unemployment</option>
            <option letter="d">Increasing aggregate demand</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Cost-push inflation typically occurs with rising unemployment because higher costs reduce production and employment while raising prices, creating stagflation.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="65">
        <prompt>The primary purpose of holding precautionary money balances is to:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Earn interest</option>
            <option letter="b">Make planned purchases</option>
            <option letter="c">Handle unexpected expenses</option>
            <option letter="d">Conduct daily transactions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Precautionary money balances are held as a buffer against unexpected expenses or emergencies, distinct from transaction balances used for planned purchases.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="66">
        <prompt>A sustained increase in productivity would:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Shift only the SRAS curve right</option>
            <option letter="b">Shift only the LRAS curve right</option>
            <option letter="c">Shift both SRAS and LRAS curves right</option>
            <option letter="d">Shift the AD curve right</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Increased productivity enhances the economy's ability to produce in both short and long run, shifting both SRAS and LRAS curves rightward.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="67">
        <prompt>Real GDP per capita is best used to measure:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Price stability</option>
            <option letter="b">Economic growth</option>
            <option letter="c">Income inequality</option>
            <option letter="d">Standard of living</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>Real GDP per capita, by accounting for both population and inflation, provides the best basic measure of average standard of living in an economy.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="68">
        <prompt>The credit multiplier will be larger when:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Required reserve ratios increase</option>
            <option letter="b">Banks hold more excess reserves</option>
            <option letter="c">The currency drain ratio increases</option>
            <option letter="d">Required reserve ratios decrease</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>Lower required reserve ratios allow banks to create more credit from each dollar of deposits, increasing the credit multiplier.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="69">
        <prompt>A decrease in business taxes would most directly affect which component of aggregate demand?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Consumption</option>
            <option letter="b">Investment</option>
            <option letter="c">Government spending</option>
            <option letter="d">Net exports</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Lower business taxes increase the expected return on investment projects, directly affecting investment spending as firms have more after-tax income for capital expenditures.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="70">
        <prompt>What happens to equilibrium price and output when both AD and SRAS increase?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Price increases, output increases</option>
            <option letter="b">Price increases, output decreases</option>
            <option letter="c">Price effect is ambiguous, output increases</option>
            <option letter="d">Price decreases, output increases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>When both AD and SRAS increase, output definitely increases, but the price effect depends on the relative magnitude of the shifts in AD and SRAS.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="71">
        <prompt>Cost-push inflation can result from which of the following?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in consumer spending</option>
            <option letter="b">An increase in government spending</option>
            <option letter="c">A decrease in raw material prices</option>
            <option letter="d">An increase in oil prices</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>Cost-push inflation occurs when production costs rise, such as through higher oil prices, causing the SRAS curve to shift left and pushing up the price level.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="72">
        <prompt>When the economy is operating below potential GDP, which gap exists?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Inflationary gap</option>
            <option letter="b">Recessionary gap</option>
            <option letter="c">Production gap</option>
            <option letter="d">Supply gap</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>A recessionary gap exists when actual real GDP is less than potential GDP, indicating the economy is operating below its full-employment level.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="73">
        <prompt>If nominal GDP is $800 billion and real GDP is $500 billion, what is the GDP deflator?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">60</option>
            <option letter="b">120</option>
            <option letter="c">160</option>
            <option letter="d">200</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The GDP deflator is calculated as (Nominal GDP/Real GDP) × 100. Therefore, ($800 billion/$500 billion) × 100 = 160.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="74">
        <prompt>Which would most likely cause the natural rate of unemployment to increase?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A decrease in aggregate demand</option>
            <option letter="b">An increase in the minimum wage</option>
            <option letter="c">A decrease in government spending</option>
            <option letter="d">An increase in the money supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>An increase in the minimum wage can increase structural unemployment by creating a price floor in the labor market, thus raising the natural rate of unemployment.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="75">
        <prompt>When the Fed engages in expansionary open market operations, it:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Sells government securities</option>
            <option letter="b">Buys government securities</option>
            <option letter="c">Raises the discount rate</option>
            <option letter="d">Increases reserve requirements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>In expansionary open market operations, the Fed buys government securities, increasing the money supply and putting downward pressure on interest rates.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="76">
        <prompt>Real GDP will be less than potential GDP when there is:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Only frictional unemployment</option>
            <option letter="b">Only structural unemployment</option>
            <option letter="c">Cyclical unemployment</option>
            <option letter="d">Full employment</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The presence of cyclical unemployment indicates the economy is operating below its potential, meaning real GDP is less than potential GDP.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="77">
        <prompt>The Fisher Effect states that a one percentage point increase in expected inflation leads to:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A one percentage point decrease in nominal interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">A one percentage point increase in nominal interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">A one percentage point increase in real interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">No change in nominal interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The Fisher Effect states that the nominal interest rate changes point-for-point with expected inflation, keeping the real interest rate constant.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="78">
        <prompt>A country's balance of payments must always:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Equal zero</option>
            <option letter="b">Be in surplus</option>
            <option letter="c">Equal the trade balance</option>
            <option letter="d">Equal the capital account</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The balance of payments must always sum to zero because all international transactions have offsetting entries in either the current or capital accounts.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="79">
        <prompt>Automatic stabilizers work by:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Requiring congressional approval</option>
            <option letter="b">Reducing aggregate supply during recessions</option>
            <option letter="c">Automatically adjusting government spending and tax revenues</option>
            <option letter="d">Increasing interest rates during expansions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Automatic stabilizers like unemployment benefits and progressive taxes automatically adjust government spending and tax revenues to help stabilize the economy.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="80">
        <prompt>The classical dichotomy implies that:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money affects both real and nominal variables</option>
            <option letter="b">Money affects only nominal variables</option>
            <option letter="c">Money affects only real variables</option>
            <option letter="d">Money has no economic effects</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The classical dichotomy states that changes in the money supply affect only nominal variables (like prices) and not real variables (like output) in the long run.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="81">
        <prompt>The term "liquidity trap" describes a situation where:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Interest rates are too high</option>
            <option letter="b">Banks have excess reserves</option>
            <option letter="c">Monetary policy becomes ineffective at zero interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">The money supply grows too quickly</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>A liquidity trap occurs when interest rates are near zero and monetary policy becomes ineffective because people prefer holding money to bonds.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="82">
        <prompt>Purchasing power parity implies that:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">All countries have the same price level</option>
            <option letter="b">Exchange rates adjust to equalize prices across countries</option>
            <option letter="c">Trade balances must be zero</option>
            <option letter="d">Interest rates are equal across countries</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Purchasing power parity theory suggests exchange rates will adjust so that the same good costs the same amount in different countries when converted to the same currency.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="83">
        <prompt>The sacrifice ratio measures the:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Trade-off between unemployment and economic growth</option>
            <option letter="b">Cost of reducing inflation in terms of lost output</option>
            <option letter="c">Relationship between interest rates and investment</option>
            <option letter="d">Trade-off between consumption and investment</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The sacrifice ratio measures how much output must be sacrificed (in percentage terms) to reduce inflation by one percentage point.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="84">
        <prompt>If the marginal propensity to consume is 0.75, the tax multiplier will be:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">-4.0</option>
            <option letter="b">-3.0</option>
            <option letter="c">-2.0</option>
            <option letter="d">-1.0</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The tax multiplier equals -MPC/(1-MPC). With MPC = 0.75, the tax multiplier is -0.75/(1-0.75) = -3.0.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="85">
        <prompt>The money multiplier would decrease if:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Banks reduce their excess reserves</option>
            <option letter="b">The required reserve ratio decreases</option>
            <option letter="c">The public holds more currency relative to deposits</option>
            <option letter="d">The discount rate is lowered</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>When the public holds more currency instead of deposits, banks have fewer deposits to multiply through lending, reducing the money multiplier.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="86">
        <prompt>During a recession, cyclical unemployment:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Equals the natural rate of unemployment</option>
            <option letter="b">Is negative</option>
            <option letter="c">Is positive</option>
            <option letter="d">Does not affect the unemployment rate</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>During recessions, cyclical unemployment is positive because actual unemployment exceeds the natural rate due to insufficient aggregate demand.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="87">
        <prompt>The primary difference between GDP and GNP is the treatment of:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">Net exports</option>
            <option letter="c">Net factor payments from abroad</option>
            <option letter="d">Transfer payments</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>GNP differs from GDP by including net factor payments from abroad, which represent income earned by domestic factors abroad minus income earned by foreign factors domestically.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="88">
        <prompt>Which policy combination would most effectively combat both unemployment and inflation?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Expansionary fiscal and monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="b">Contractionary fiscal and monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="c">Supply-side policies and demand management</option>
            <option letter="d">Increased taxes and decreased interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Supply-side policies can increase potential output while demand management can control inflation, addressing both problems simultaneously.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="89">
        <prompt>A shift from saving to consumption in the private sector would most likely result in:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in the real interest rate</option>
            <option letter="b">A decrease in the real interest rate</option>
            <option letter="c">An increase in investment</option>
            <option letter="d">No change in the real interest rate</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>A decrease in saving relative to consumption reduces the supply of loanable funds, pushing up the real interest rate in the loanable funds market.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="90">
        <prompt>Which of the following would cause stagflation?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A decrease in government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">An increase in the money supply</option>
            <option letter="c">A negative supply shock</option>
            <option letter="d">A decrease in consumer confidence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>A negative supply shock shifts SRAS left, causing both higher prices (inflation) and lower output (stagnation), which defines stagflation.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="91">
        <prompt>The natural rate of unemployment is equal to:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Frictional unemployment only</option>
            <option letter="b">Structural unemployment only</option>
            <option letter="c">Cyclical unemployment only</option>
            <option letter="d">Frictional plus structural unemployment</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>The natural rate of unemployment consists of frictional unemployment (normal job transitions) plus structural unemployment (skills/location mismatches).</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="92">
        <prompt>A decrease in net exports will:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increase aggregate supply</option>
            <option letter="b">Decrease aggregate demand</option>
            <option letter="c">Increase the price level</option>
            <option letter="d">Have no effect on aggregate demand</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Net exports are a component of aggregate demand; a decrease in net exports reduces total spending in the economy, shifting the AD curve left.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="93">
        <prompt>In the AS/AD model, which combination represents stagflation?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Rising prices and rising output</option>
            <option letter="b">Falling prices and falling output</option>
            <option letter="c">Rising prices and falling output</option>
            <option letter="d">Falling prices and rising output</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Stagflation occurs when the economy experiences both inflation (rising prices) and stagnation (falling output), typically caused by negative supply shocks shifting SRAS left.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="94">
        <prompt>If the required reserve ratio is 10% and banks hold no excess reserves, what is the money multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">0.1</option>
            <option letter="b">1.0</option>
            <option letter="c">10.0</option>
            <option letter="d">100.0</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The money multiplier equals 1/required reserve ratio. With a 10% (0.1) required reserve ratio, the money multiplier is 1/0.1 = 10.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="95">
        <prompt>Which would most likely result from a depreciation of the domestic currency?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Decrease in exports, increase in imports</option>
            <option letter="b">Increase in exports, decrease in imports</option>
            <option letter="c">Increase in both exports and imports</option>
            <option letter="d">Decrease in both exports and imports</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Currency depreciation makes domestic goods cheaper for foreigners (increasing exports) and foreign goods more expensive for domestic buyers (decreasing imports).</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="96">
        <prompt>Which policy would be most appropriate to combat a severe recession?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increasing interest rates and government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">Decreasing interest rates and taxes</option>
            <option letter="c">Increasing interest rates and taxes</option>
            <option letter="d">Decreasing interest rates and government spending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>To combat recession, expansionary monetary policy (lower interest rates) and expansionary fiscal policy (lower taxes) would work together to increase aggregate demand.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="97">
        <prompt>Which fiscal policy combination would be most appropriate during an inflationary gap?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Decrease taxes and increase government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">Increase taxes and decrease government spending</option>
            <option letter="c">Increase both taxes and government spending</option>
            <option letter="d">Decrease both taxes and government spending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>During an inflationary gap, contractionary fiscal policy is needed. Increasing taxes and decreasing government spending both work to reduce aggregate demand and close the inflationary gap.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="98">
        <prompt>An increase in the velocity of money would most likely cause:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A decrease in the price level</option>
            <option letter="b">A decrease in nominal GDP</option>
            <option letter="c">An increase in the price level</option>
            <option letter="d">No change in the price level</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>According to the quantity theory of money, an increase in velocity, holding money supply constant, leads to higher nominal GDP and price level as each dollar is used more frequently in transactions.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="99">
        <prompt>If the MPC is 0.8, the multiplier effect of a $100 billion increase in government spending would be:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$400 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">$500 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$800 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$1000 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With an MPC of 0.8, the multiplier is 1/(1-0.8) = 5. Therefore, a $100 billion increase in spending results in a $500 billion increase in GDP.</explanation>
    </question>

    <question number="100">
        <prompt>A decrease in net exports would shift the:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">AD curve right</option>
            <option letter="b">AD curve left</option>
            <option letter="c">SRAS curve right</option>
            <option letter="d">SRAS curve left</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Net exports are a component of aggregate demand. A decrease in net exports reduces total spending in the economy, shifting the AD curve to the left.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>