<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz><question number="1">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Federal Elections Bill of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To protect African American voting rights in the South</option>
            <option letter="b">To restrict voting rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To eliminate polling places</option>
            <option letter="d">To support state control</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Federal Elections Bill attempted to protect African American voting rights through federal supervision of Southern elections, but failed to pass the Senate.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="2">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the National Farmers Alliance Exchange?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To create a cooperative system for buying and selling farm products</option>
            <option letter="b">To support large corporations</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase merchant profits</option>
            <option letter="d">To restrict trade</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Farmers Alliance Exchange attempted to create a cooperative system for farmers to buy supplies and sell crops, bypassing merchants and middlemen.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="3">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Supreme Court's E.C. Knight decision?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It limited the government's ability to break up manufacturing monopolies</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened antitrust laws</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected small businesses</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased regulation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The E.C. Knight decision limited the Sherman Antitrust Act by ruling that manufacturing was not interstate commerce, protecting manufacturing monopolies from federal regulation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="4">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Chautauqua movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To provide adult education and cultural programs</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote political parties</option>
            <option letter="c">To support business interests</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose reform movements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Chautauqua movement provided adult education and cultural programs to rural communities, helping to spread progressive ideas and cultural enrichment.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="5">
        <prompt>What was the main argument used to justify American imperialism?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">White Americans had a duty to civilize other peoples</option>
            <option letter="b">Military conquest was profitable</option>
            <option letter="c">Territorial expansion was necessary</option>
            <option letter="d">Other nations threatened U.S. interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The idea of "The White Man's Burden" and social Darwinism were used to justify American imperialism as a moral duty to civilize and Christianize other peoples.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="6">
        <prompt>What was the major impact of the depression of 1893-1897?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It led to widespread unemployment and labor unrest</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">It increased industrial production</option>
            <option letter="d">It improved working conditions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The depression caused massive unemployment, widespread business failures, and significant labor unrest, becoming one of the worst economic crises of the 19th century.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="7">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Immigration Restriction League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect immigrant rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote cultural diversity</option>
            <option letter="d">To assist immigrant settlement</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Immigration Restriction League sought to limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe, arguing these immigrants were racially and culturally inferior to earlier Northern European immigrants.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="8">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the massacre at Wounded Knee in 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It marked the end of organized Native American resistance</option>
            <option letter="b">It led to improved Indian policies</option>
            <option letter="c">It started the Ghost Dance movement</option>
            <option letter="d">It united tribal nations</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The massacre at Wounded Knee effectively marked the end of organized Native American military resistance to U.S. expansion and symbolized the triumph of federal power over native peoples.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="9">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Alaska purchase in 1867?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To secure strategic territory and natural resources</option>
            <option letter="b">To establish new farming settlements</option>
            <option letter="c">To prevent British expansion</option>
            <option letter="d">To create Native American reservations</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Secretary of State William Seward pursued the Alaska purchase to secure strategic territory and natural resources, though critics called it "Seward's Folly" until the discovery of gold in the late 1890s.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="10">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the separate but equal doctrine?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It provided legal justification for systematic segregation</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted racial integration</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected minority rights</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased educational funding</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The separate but equal doctrine, established by Plessy v. Ferguson, provided legal justification for systematic racial segregation across the South and beyond.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="11">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of yellow journalism in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It helped create public support for the Spanish-American War</option>
            <option letter="b">It improved journalistic accuracy</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced newspaper circulation</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted international peace</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Yellow journalism, particularly by Hearst and Pulitzer's newspapers, used sensationalized stories about Spanish atrocities to build public support for war with Spain.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="12">
        <prompt>What was the primary motivation for U.S. imperialism in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Economic expansion and strategic military interests</option>
            <option letter="b">Spreading democracy</option>
            <option letter="c">Humanitarian concerns</option>
            <option letter="d">Cultural exchange</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>U.S. imperialism was primarily motivated by the desire for new markets, strategic military bases, and the belief that national greatness required overseas expansion.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="13">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the League of American Wheelmen?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote cycling and advocate for better roads</option>
            <option letter="b">To restrict bicycle use</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase bicycle prices</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose transportation reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The League of American Wheelmen promoted cycling and advocated for road improvements, contributing to the Good Roads Movement of the 1890s.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="14">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the United Confederate Veterans?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote the Lost Cause interpretation of the Civil War</option>
            <option letter="b">To support reconstruction</option>
            <option letter="c">To advocate civil rights</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose segregation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The United Confederate Veterans promoted the Lost Cause interpretation of the Civil War, helping to justify segregation and white supremacy in the South.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="15">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Warehouse Act of 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It attempted to help farmers store and market their crops</option>
            <option letter="b">It benefited large corporations</option>
            <option letter="c">It restricted grain storage</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased storage costs</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Warehouse Act attempted to help farmers by providing facilities to store their crops until prices improved, though it had limited success.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="16">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the American Railway Union?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To unite all railroad workers in one industrial union</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect company interests</option>
            <option letter="c">To prevent strikes</option>
            <option letter="d">To support management</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Eugene V. Debs's American Railway Union attempted to unite all railroad workers in one industrial union, challenging the craft union model of the era.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="17">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of Jim Crow laws in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To establish complete racial segregation in public life</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect African American rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote racial equality</option>
            <option letter="d">To reform education</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Jim Crow laws were designed to establish and maintain complete racial segregation in all aspects of public life, creating a comprehensive system of white supremacy.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="18">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Sherman Silver Purchase Act of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To increase the amount of silver the government purchased monthly</option>
            <option letter="b">To establish the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce silver mining</option>
            <option letter="d">To stabilize currency value</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Sherman Silver Purchase Act required the government to purchase 4.5 million ounces of silver monthly, more than double the previous amount, in an attempt to help silver producers.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="19">
        <prompt>What role did the NAACP play in challenging segregation?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It used legal action to challenge discriminatory laws</option>
            <option letter="b">It organized mass protests</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted economic boycotts</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported political candidates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The NAACP, founded in 1909, focused primarily on using legal action to challenge segregation and discrimination in the courts, establishing a pattern of civil rights litigation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="20">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Spanish-American War on American society?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established the United States as a world power</option>
            <option letter="b">It united North and South</option>
            <option letter="c">It improved race relations</option>
            <option letter="d">It strengthened isolationism</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Spanish-American War established the United States as a world power with overseas territories, marking a significant shift toward American imperialism and international influence.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="21">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Atlanta Exposition of 1895?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To showcase the New South's industrial progress</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote civil rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To celebrate Confederate history</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose industrialization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Atlanta Exposition was designed to showcase the South's industrial development and attract Northern investment, providing the setting for Booker T. Washington's famous compromise speech.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="22">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Jane Addams's Hull House?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered settlement house work in American cities</option>
            <option letter="b">It provided only housing assistance</option>
            <option letter="c">It focused on rural poverty</option>
            <option letter="d">It served only immigrant women</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Hull House pioneered the settlement house movement in America, providing educational, cultural, and social services to urban immigrants while promoting social reform.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="23">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of literacy tests on voting rights?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They disenfranchised African Americans through discriminatory application</option>
            <option letter="b">They improved education levels</option>
            <option letter="c">They increased voter turnout</option>
            <option letter="d">They applied equally to all races</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Literacy tests were applied discriminatorily to prevent African Americans from voting while allowing illiterate whites to vote through grandfather clauses and other exemptions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="24">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Philippine-American War?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To establish American colonial control over the Philippines</option>
            <option letter="b">To grant immediate independence</option>
            <option letter="c">To protect Filipino rights</option>
            <option letter="d">To prevent Japanese expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The U.S. fought to establish colonial control over the Philippines against Filipino independence fighters, resulting in a brutal guerrilla war and eventual American victory.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="25">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Negro Business League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote African American economic development</option>
            <option letter="b">To challenge segregation</option>
            <option letter="c">To advocate political rights</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose capitalism</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Founded by Booker T. Washington, the National Negro Business League promoted African American economic development through business ownership and entrepreneurship.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="26">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Coal Creek War?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It protested the use of convict labor in mining</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported prison labor</option>
            <option letter="c">It improved working conditions</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased wages</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Coal Creek War was a miners' uprising against the use of convict labor in Tennessee coal mines, highlighting labor-management conflicts.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="27">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Social Gospel movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It applied Christian principles to social problems</option>
            <option letter="b">It opposed reform efforts</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported laissez-faire</option>
            <option letter="d">It ignored urban issues</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Social Gospel movement applied Christian principles to address social problems like poverty, inequality, and urban conditions, promoting reform through religious activism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="28">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the American Beauty Steel Rose?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To symbolize the costs of industrial progress</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote steel sales</option>
            <option letter="c">To support art only</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose industry</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The American Beauty Steel Rose became a symbol of the human and environmental costs of industrial progress, particularly in literature and social criticism.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="29">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the White Man's Burden ideology?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To justify American imperialism as a civilizing mission</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote racial equality</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose colonialism</option>
            <option letter="d">To support independence movements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Rudyard Kipling's poem "The White Man's Burden" promoted the idea that white Americans and Europeans had a duty to civilize and Christianize "inferior" peoples, justifying imperialism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="30">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the merger movement of the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It created large industrial corporations through consolidation</option>
            <option letter="b">It increased business competition</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected small businesses</option>
            <option letter="d">It reduced industrial efficiency</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The merger movement resulted in the consolidation of many smaller companies into large corporations, creating industrial giants that dominated their respective industries.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="31">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of Eugene V. Debs's Social Democratic Party?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote socialist policies and worker ownership</option>
            <option letter="b">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="c">To maintain capitalism</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Debs's Social Democratic Party, later the Socialist Party of America, advocated for worker ownership of the means of production and other socialist policies.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="32">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the de Lôme letter incident?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It increased public support for war with Spain</option>
            <option letter="b">It improved Spanish-American relations</option>
            <option letter="c">It prevented war</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported Spanish policy</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The publication of Spanish diplomat de Lôme's letter criticizing President McKinley increased anti-Spanish sentiment and public support for war with Spain.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="33">
        <prompt>What was the primary significance of the Insular Cases (1901)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They established that the Constitution did not fully apply to U.S. territories</option>
            <option letter="b">They granted full citizenship to territorial residents</option>
            <option letter="c">They required territorial independence</option>
            <option letter="d">They prohibited U.S. expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court's decisions in the Insular Cases established that the Constitution did not automatically extend in full to U.S. territories, creating the concept of "unincorporated territories."</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="34">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of lynching in the 1890s South?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To maintain white supremacy through racial terrorism</option>
            <option letter="b">To enforce criminal justice</option>
            <option letter="c">To prevent property crimes</option>
            <option letter="d">To resolve personal disputes</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Lynching served as a form of racial terrorism designed to maintain white supremacy by intimidating African Americans and enforcing social and economic subordination.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="35">
        <prompt>What was the key feature of the "New South" movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It promoted industrialization while maintaining racial segregation</option>
            <option letter="b">It advocated for civil rights reform</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed economic development</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported agricultural reform only</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The New South movement promoted industrial development and economic modernization while maintaining the racial hierarchy through segregation and disfranchisement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="36">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of the Chinese Exclusion Act's extension in 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It made Chinese exclusion permanent and required registration</option>
            <option letter="b">It allowed increased Chinese immigration</option>
            <option letter="c">It granted citizenship to Chinese residents</option>
            <option letter="d">It improved conditions for Chinese Americans</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Geary Act of 1892 extended the Chinese Exclusion Act for another ten years and required all Chinese residents to register and obtain certificates of residence or face deportation.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="37">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the General Federation of Women's Clubs?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To coordinate women's reform activities nationally</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose women's rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To support traditional roles</option>
            <option letter="d">To prevent reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The GFWC coordinated women's clubs nationally to promote reform activities, including education, public health, and municipal improvement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="38">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Single Tax movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It proposed land value taxation to address inequality</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported multiple taxes</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed all taxation</option>
            <option letter="d">It favored the wealthy</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Henry George's Single Tax movement proposed taxing land values to address inequality and speculation, influencing progressive reform thought.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="39">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Second International's formation?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It connected American socialists to the global movement</option>
            <option letter="b">It isolated American labor</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed socialism</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported capitalism</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Second International connected American socialists to the global socialist movement, though tensions existed over tactics and goals.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="40">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Niagara Movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To demand immediate equal rights for African Americans</option>
            <option letter="b">To support gradual change</option>
            <option letter="c">To accept segregation</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose activism</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Niagara Movement demanded immediate equal rights for African Americans, rejecting Booker T. Washington's accommodationist approach.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="41">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the National American Woman Suffrage Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To win women's voting rights through state-by-state campaigns</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote prohibition</option>
            <option letter="c">To secure equal pay for women</option>
            <option letter="d">To reform marriage laws</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>NAWSA, formed in 1890, focused primarily on achieving women's suffrage through state-by-state campaigns rather than pursuing a federal amendment or broader women's rights issues.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="42">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Kansas Exodus of 1879-1880?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated African Americans' willingness to leave the South for freedom</option>
            <option letter="b">It led to improved conditions in the South</option>
            <option letter="c">It resulted in significant land grants</option>
            <option letter="d">It ended racial violence in Kansas</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Exodus of thousands of African Americans to Kansas showed their determination to escape Southern oppression, though many faced hardship in their new homes.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="43">
        <prompt>What was the significance of William Jennings Bryan's "Cross of Gold" speech?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It united the Democratic and Populist parties behind free silver</option>
            <option letter="b">It won him the presidency</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="d">It advocated for banking reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Bryan's dramatic speech at the 1896 Democratic Convention united the Democratic and Populist parties behind the free silver cause, though he ultimately lost the election.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="44">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of state constitutional disfranchisement provisions?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To legally eliminate African American voting while avoiding federal intervention</option>
            <option letter="b">To prevent voter fraud</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase voter participation</option>
            <option letter="d">To simplify voting procedures</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Southern states used various constitutional provisions like literacy tests and poll taxes to legally eliminate African American voting rights while avoiding direct federal intervention.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="45">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the Rough Riders' charge up San Juan Hill?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It became a symbol of American heroism in the Spanish-American War</option>
            <option letter="b">It ended the war immediately</option>
            <option letter="c">It led to Spanish victory</option>
            <option letter="d">It prevented Cuban independence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Rough Riders' charge, though actually up Kettle Hill, became a celebrated symbol of American heroism and helped launch Theodore Roosevelt's political career.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="46">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Cleveland-Morgan deal during the 1895 financial crisis?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To maintain the gold standard by selling bonds to a banking syndicate</option>
            <option letter="b">To adopt free silver</option>
            <option letter="c">To nationalize banks</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase inflation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>President Cleveland worked with J.P. Morgan to maintain the gold standard by selling government bonds to a banking syndicate, preventing a financial collapse.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="47">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the People's Party (Populists) in the 1892 election?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To represent farmers' and workers' interests against industrial capitalism</option>
            <option letter="b">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="c">To maintain the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote industrial growth</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Populists sought to represent farmers and workers against industrial capitalism, advocating for monetary reform, government ownership of railroads, and other reforms.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="48">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Battle of Manila Bay?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established American naval superiority in the Pacific</option>
            <option letter="b">It secured Philippine independence</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected Spanish interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It prevented colonial expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Commodore Dewey's victory at Manila Bay destroyed the Spanish fleet, established American naval superiority in the Pacific, and led to U.S. acquisition of the Philippines.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="49">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the "Remember the Maine" slogan?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To rally public support for war with Spain</option>
            <option letter="b">To honor fallen sailors</option>
            <option letter="c">To raise funds for the navy</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote naval reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The slogan "Remember the Maine" was used by yellow journalists and war hawks to rally public support for war with Spain after the battleship's explosion in Havana harbor.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="50">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Sherman Anti-Trust Act of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It was initially used more against labor unions than trusts</option>
            <option letter="b">It immediately broke up major monopolies</option>
            <option letter="c">It strengthened worker rights</option>
            <option letter="d">It reduced business consolidation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Despite its intended purpose to break up monopolies, the Sherman Anti-Trust Act was initially used more frequently against labor unions than against business trusts.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="51">
        <prompt>What was the significance of William McKinley's election in 1896?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It marked the triumph of big business and the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="b">It led to free silver coinage</option>
            <option letter="c">It strengthened the Populist Party</option>
            <option letter="d">It reduced corporate influence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>McKinley's victory represented the triumph of big business interests and the gold standard over the Populist-Democratic fusion and free silver movement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="52">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Interstate Commerce Act of 1887?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To regulate railroad rates and practices</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote railroad expansion</option>
            <option letter="c">To nationalize railroads</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect railroad profits</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Interstate Commerce Act was designed to regulate railroad rates and practices, particularly to prevent rate discrimination and other unfair practices affecting shippers.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="53">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Forest Reserve Act of 1891?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To protect public forests from private exploitation</option>
            <option letter="b">To increase logging</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote settlement</option>
            <option letter="d">To generate revenue</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Forest Reserve Act authorized the president to set aside public forests as reserves, protecting them from private exploitation and marking the beginning of federal conservation policy.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="54">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Paddock Pure Food Bill?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It was an early attempt at federal food regulation</option>
            <option letter="b">It successfully regulated food industry</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced government oversight</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased food prices</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Though it failed to pass, the Paddock Pure Food Bill represented an important early attempt at federal regulation of food safety and purity.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="55">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Pan-American Conference of 1889?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established U.S. leadership in hemispheric affairs</option>
            <option letter="b">It created free trade</option>
            <option letter="c">It united American nations</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed U.S. influence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Pan-American Conference established U.S. leadership in hemispheric affairs, though it failed to achieve its specific goals of customs union and arbitration treaties.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="56">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the National Market Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To organize farmers' cooperative marketing efforts</option>
            <option letter="b">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="c">To regulate trade</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase prices</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Market Association attempted to organize farmers' cooperative marketing efforts to bypass middlemen and get better prices for agricultural products.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="57">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Industrial Christian Alliance?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To combine religious salvation with economic assistance</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose labor unions</option>
            <option letter="c">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="d">To prevent reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Industrial Christian Alliance combined religious salvation with practical economic assistance for urban workers, reflecting Social Gospel principles.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="58">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Message to Garcia?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It promoted individual initiative and loyalty to employers</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported labor rights</option>
            <option letter="c">It criticized business</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed capitalism</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>This widely circulated essay promoted individual initiative and unquestioning loyalty to employers, becoming a popular management tool.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="59">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Trans-Mississippi Exposition?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It promoted Western development and American imperialism</option>
            <option letter="b">It opposed expansion</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported isolationism</option>
            <option letter="d">It criticized progress</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The 1898 Trans-Mississippi Exposition in Omaha celebrated Western development while promoting American imperialism and technological progress.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="60">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Catholic Indian Missions?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To convert Native Americans while preserving some traditions</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose assimilation</option>
            <option letter="c">To support tribal sovereignty</option>
            <option letter="d">To prevent education</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Catholic Indian Missions sought to convert Native Americans to Catholicism while being more tolerant of traditional practices than Protestant missionaries.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="61">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Prison Congress?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote prison reform and rehabilitation</option>
            <option letter="b">To increase punishment</option>
            <option letter="c">To expand prisons</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Prison Congress promoted prison reform and rehabilitation programs, reflecting progressive ideas about crime and punishment.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="62">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Tuskegee Institute?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It provided industrial education while accepting segregation</option>
            <option letter="b">It demanded integration</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed education</option>
            <option letter="d">It challenged Jim Crow</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Under Booker T. Washington, Tuskegee Institute provided industrial education for African Americans while accepting racial segregation temporarily.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="63">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Supreme Court's Civil Rights Cases?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It severely limited federal civil rights enforcement</option>
            <option letter="b">It expanded civil rights</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected equality</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed segregation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The 1883 Civil Rights Cases severely limited federal power to protect civil rights by ruling that the 14th Amendment only restricted state actions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="64">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Knights of Labor's reform program?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To create a cooperative industrial system</option>
            <option letter="b">To support capitalism</option>
            <option letter="c">To limit worker rights</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose change</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Knights of Labor advocated for a cooperative industrial system to replace wage labor, though they ultimately failed to achieve this goal.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="65">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of Benjamin Harrison's foreign policy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It expanded American influence in the Pacific and Latin America</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted isolation</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced naval power</option>
            <option letter="d">It avoided foreign conflicts</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Harrison's foreign policy expanded American influence through naval expansion, the Pan-American Conference, and attempts to acquire Pacific bases like Pearl Harbor.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="66">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Farmers' Mutual Benefit Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It organized farmers for economic cooperation and political action</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported industrial interests</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed agricultural reform</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted urbanization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Farmers' Mutual Benefit Association organized farmers for economic cooperation and political action, contributing to the broader agrarian reform movement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="67">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Lodge Force Bill?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To protect African American voting rights through federal supervision</option>
            <option letter="b">To restrict voting rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To support state control</option>
            <option letter="d">To limit federal power</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Lodge Force Bill attempted to protect African American voting rights through federal supervision of elections, but failed to pass due to Southern opposition.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="68">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the Ocala Demands?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It unified farmer organizations behind a common reform program</option>
            <option letter="b">It divided agricultural interests</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported big business</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed political action</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Ocala Demands united various farmer organizations behind a common program of reform, including government ownership of railroads and free silver coinage.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="69">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Teller Amendment?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promise Cuba's independence after Spanish defeat</option>
            <option letter="b">To annex Cuba permanently</option>
            <option letter="c">To establish a military base</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect Spanish interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Teller Amendment promised that the United States would not annex Cuba after defeating Spain, though the later Platt Amendment would limit Cuban independence.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="70">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of the McKinley Tariff of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It raised tariff rates to their highest peacetime level</option>
            <option letter="b">It reduced import taxes</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted free trade</option>
            <option letter="d">It decreased consumer prices</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The McKinley Tariff raised import duties to their highest peacetime level, protecting American industry but contributing to higher consumer prices and international trade tensions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="71">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Indian Citizenship Act of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote Native American assimilation through land allotment</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect tribal sovereignty</option>
            <option letter="c">To preserve Native culture</option>
            <option letter="d">To expand tribal lands</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Act aimed to assimilate Native Americans by breaking up tribal lands into individual allotments and granting citizenship to those who adopted European-American farming practices.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="72">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of the National Association of Colored Women?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote racial advancement through education and social service</option>
            <option letter="b">To focus solely on suffrage</option>
            <option letter="c">To support segregation</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose women's rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The NACW worked to promote racial advancement through education, social services, and civil rights activism, adopting the motto "Lifting as We Climb."</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="73">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Populist Party's fusion with Democrats in 1896?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It led to the decline of the Populist movement</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened both parties</option>
            <option letter="c">It secured victory in the election</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted radical reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The fusion with Democrats in support of William Jennings Bryan led to the decline of the independent Populist movement, as the party lost its distinctive identity.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="74">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of Jim Crow etiquette?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To reinforce black subordination through daily social interactions</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote racial harmony</option>
            <option letter="c">To protect civil rights</option>
            <option letter="d">To improve race relations</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Jim Crow etiquette enforced black subordination through detailed rules governing daily interactions between races, reinforcing white supremacy through social customs.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="75">
        <prompt>What was the main argument of Henry George's Progress and Poverty?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Poverty resulted from private land ownership and speculation</option>
            <option letter="b">Industrial growth caused prosperity</option>
            <option letter="c">Free trade eliminated poverty</option>
            <option letter="d">Government regulation was needed</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>George argued that poverty persisted amid progress because private land ownership and speculation allowed landowners to unfairly profit from society's advancement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="76">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Buffalo Soldiers in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They served as elite African American cavalry units in the West</option>
            <option letter="b">They led civil rights protests</option>
            <option letter="c">They opposed U.S. expansion</option>
            <option letter="d">They supported Native American rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Buffalo Soldiers were elite African American cavalry units that served in the West and later in the Spanish-American War, despite facing racial discrimination.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="77">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Australian ballot system?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It reduced electoral corruption through secret voting</option>
            <option letter="b">It increased voter participation</option>
            <option letter="c">It simplified voting procedures</option>
            <option letter="d">It expanded voting rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Australian ballot system reduced electoral corruption by providing standardized, government-printed ballots and secret voting, though it also confused some illiterate voters.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="78">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Cambridge School controversy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It challenged separate but equal education in the North</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported segregation</option>
            <option letter="c">It improved school funding</option>
            <option letter="d">It expanded education access</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Cambridge School controversy challenged racial segregation in Northern schools, highlighting that Jim Crow practices weren't limited to the South.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="79">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Cordage Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To control rope production and prices through monopoly</option>
            <option letter="b">To improve product quality</option>
            <option letter="c">To protect workers</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote competition</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Cordage Association attempted to monopolize rope production and control prices, though its collapse in 1893 helped trigger the economic depression.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="80">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the National Civil Service Reform League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To eliminate the spoils system through merit-based hiring</option>
            <option letter="b">To expand patronage</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce government jobs</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase political control</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Civil Service Reform League worked to eliminate the spoils system and establish merit-based hiring for government positions.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="81">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Cuban Reconcentration Policy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To suppress Cuban independence by relocating civilians</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect Cuban civilians</option>
            <option letter="c">To provide humanitarian aid</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote Cuban autonomy</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Spain's reconcentration policy forced Cuban civilians into camps to deny support to rebels, resulting in widespread death from disease and starvation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="82">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Supreme Court's E.C. Knight decision?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It limited the government's ability to break up manufacturing monopolies</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened antitrust enforcement</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected worker rights</option>
            <option letter="d">It regulated interstate commerce</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The 1895 E.C. Knight decision limited the Sherman Antitrust Act by ruling that manufacturing was not interstate commerce, protecting many monopolies from federal regulation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="83">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of the National Consumers League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To improve working conditions through consumer pressure</option>
            <option letter="b">To reduce consumer prices</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose labor unions</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote free trade</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Consumers League worked to improve working conditions and end child labor by educating and mobilizing consumers to support businesses with good labor practices.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="84">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of Ellis Island?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To process and inspect European immigrants</option>
            <option letter="b">To restrict immigration</option>
            <option letter="c">To deport immigrants</option>
            <option letter="d">To provide housing</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Ellis Island served as the main processing center for European immigrants, where they underwent medical and legal inspections before being allowed to enter the United States.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="85">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of William McKinley's front porch campaign in 1896?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To project a conservative, dignified image in contrast to Bryan</option>
            <option letter="b">To save campaign travel expenses</option>
            <option letter="c">To avoid public speaking</option>
            <option letter="d">To focus solely on Ohio voters</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>McKinley's front porch campaign strategy allowed him to project a dignified, conservative image while Bryan's whistle-stop touring appeared radical and unstable to many voters.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="86">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Civil Rights Cases decision of 1883?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To limit federal power to protect civil rights</option>
            <option letter="b">To expand civil rights protections</option>
            <option letter="c">To enforce the 14th Amendment</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote racial equality</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court's decision in the Civil Rights Cases severely limited federal power to protect civil rights by ruling that the 14th Amendment only applied to state, not private, actions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="87">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the American Federation of Labor's founding?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established craft unionism as the dominant labor organization model</option>
            <option letter="b">It united all workers regardless of skill</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted socialist ideology</option>
            <option letter="d">It focused on unskilled laborers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The AFL, under Samuel Gompers, established craft unionism focused on skilled workers as the dominant form of labor organization, rejecting both industrial unionism and political radicalism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="88">
        <prompt>What was the main result of the Treaty of Paris of 1898?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Spain ceded control of Cuba, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Philippines</option>
            <option letter="b">The U.S. gained control of Hawaii</option>
            <option letter="c">Spain retained control of Cuba</option>
            <option letter="d">The Philippines gained independence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Treaty of Paris ending the Spanish-American War resulted in Spain ceding control of Cuba, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Philippines to the United States for $20 million.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="89">
        <prompt>What was the primary impact of the Lost Cause ideology in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It romanticized the Confederate cause and justified segregation</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted racial reconciliation</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported civil rights legislation</option>
            <option letter="d">It encouraged Northern immigration to the South</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Lost Cause ideology glorified the Confederate cause, portrayed slavery as benign, and helped justify Jim Crow laws and racial segregation in the South.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="90">
        <prompt>What was the main feature of the "New Immigration" of the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Most immigrants came from Southern and Eastern Europe</option>
            <option letter="b">Immigration rates decreased significantly</option>
            <option letter="c">Most immigrants were skilled laborers</option>
            <option letter="d">Immigrants settled primarily in rural areas</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The "New Immigration" was characterized by large numbers of immigrants from Southern and Eastern Europe, marking a shift from earlier patterns of Northern European immigration.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="91">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Eugene V. Debs's role in the Pullman Strike?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">His leadership transformed him into a national labor figure</option>
            <option letter="b">He successfully negotiated with Pullman</option>
            <option letter="c">He prevented federal intervention</option>
            <option letter="d">He won concessions for the workers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Though the strike failed, Debs's leadership of the American Railway Union during the Pullman Strike established him as a prominent national labor leader and led to his conversion to socialism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="92">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the overthrow of Queen Liliuokalani?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It led to Hawaii's eventual annexation by the United States</option>
            <option letter="b">It restored Hawaiian independence</option>
            <option letter="c">It strengthened the Hawaiian monarchy</option>
            <option letter="d">It resulted in British control of Hawaii</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The 1893 overthrow of Queen Liliuokalani by American business interests and marines led directly to the establishment of a pro-American republic and eventual U.S. annexation in 1898.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="93">
        <prompt>What was the main argument of Josiah Strong's Our Country?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Anglo-Saxons had a duty to spread civilization worldwide</option>
            <option letter="b">America should remain isolated</option>
            <option letter="c">Immigration should be encouraged</option>
            <option letter="d">Cultural diversity was beneficial</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Strong's influential book argued that Anglo-Saxons had a divine mission to spread their civilization worldwide, helping justify American imperialism and expansion.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="94">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of settlement houses?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To provide social services and education to urban immigrants</option>
            <option letter="b">To restrict immigration</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote segregation</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase property values</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Settlement houses provided education, social services, and cultural programs to urban immigrants while promoting social reform through resident workers' activism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="95">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of William McKinley's campaign strategy in 1896?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered modern campaign techniques and corporate fundraising</option>
            <option letter="b">It reduced campaign spending</option>
            <option letter="c">It alienated business interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported free silver</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>McKinley's campaign pioneered modern techniques including unprecedented corporate fundraising, sophisticated voter targeting, and extensive publicity materials.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="96">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Sewing Machine Trust?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated how patent pools could create monopolies</option>
            <option letter="b">It improved working conditions</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced product prices</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted competition</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Sewing Machine Trust showed how companies could use patent pools to create monopolies and control markets, becoming a model for other industries.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="97">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Sub-Treasury Plan?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To provide government loans to farmers using crops as collateral</option>
            <option letter="b">To support private banks</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce farm production</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Populist Sub-Treasury Plan proposed that the government establish warehouses where farmers could store crops and receive low-interest loans using them as collateral.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="98">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Haymarket Square bombing?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It discredited the labor movement by associating it with violence</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened union support</option>
            <option letter="c">It improved working conditions</option>
            <option letter="d">It united workers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Haymarket Square bombing and subsequent trial discredited the labor movement by associating it with anarchism and violence in the public mind.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="99">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of Henry George's single tax proposal?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It sparked debate about land ownership and economic inequality</option>
            <option letter="b">It was implemented nationally</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced property taxes</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased land values</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>George's proposal to tax land values sparked widespread debate about land ownership, speculation, and economic inequality, though it was never implemented.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="100">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the First International American Conference?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To establish U.S. economic leadership in the Western Hemisphere</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose European influence</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote democracy</option>
            <option letter="d">To reduce tariffs</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The First International American Conference aimed to establish U.S. economic leadership in the Western Hemisphere through trade agreements and monetary cooperation.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="101">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the American Protective Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To oppose Catholic influence in American society</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect immigrant rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote religious tolerance</option>
            <option letter="d">To support Catholic education</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The American Protective Association was an anti-Catholic organization that claimed Catholics were plotting to take over America and opposed Catholic immigration.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="102">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Wilson-Gorman Tariff of 1894?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To reduce tariff rates and implement an income tax</option>
            <option letter="b">To increase protective tariffs</option>
            <option letter="c">To eliminate all tariffs</option>
            <option letter="d">To fund internal improvements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Wilson-Gorman Tariff modestly reduced tariff rates and included a federal income tax provision, though the Supreme Court later ruled the income tax unconstitutional.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="103">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Ida B. Wells's anti-lynching campaign?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It exposed lynching as a tool of racial terrorism</option>
            <option letter="b">It ended lynching immediately</option>
            <option letter="c">It secured federal legislation</option>
            <option letter="d">It united white and black southerners</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Wells's investigative journalism and campaigns exposed lynching as a tool of racial terrorism rather than punishment for crime, bringing international attention to the practice.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="104">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Columbian Exposition of 1893?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It showcased American industrial and technological progress</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted racial equality</option>
            <option letter="c">It criticized industrialization</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Chicago World's Fair celebrated American industrial and technological achievements, promoting a vision of progress while largely excluding African American contributions.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="105">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of Joseph Pulitzer's journalism?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered mass-circulation newspapers and sensationalism</option>
            <option letter="b">It focused on objective reporting</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed yellow journalism</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported Spanish policies</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Pulitzer pioneered mass-circulation newspapers through sensationalism, human interest stories, and crusading journalism, though he was generally more responsible than Hearst.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="106">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Bland-Allison Act of 1878?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It required limited silver purchases but didn't satisfy silver advocates</option>
            <option letter="b">It established free silver coinage</option>
            <option letter="c">It ended silver purchases</option>
            <option letter="d">It stabilized currency value</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Bland-Allison Act required the Treasury to purchase some silver, but the amount was too limited to satisfy silver advocates or significantly affect the money supply.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="107">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Dawes Severalty Act?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To break up tribal lands and force Native American assimilation</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect tribal sovereignty</option>
            <option letter="c">To expand Indian reservations</option>
            <option letter="d">To preserve native culture</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Dawes Act aimed to break up tribal lands into individual allotments and force Native Americans to adopt European-American farming practices and cultural values.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="108">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the International Copyright Act of 1891?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It protected foreign authors' rights and professionalized American publishing</option>
            <option letter="b">It restricted book publication</option>
            <option letter="c">It increased book prices</option>
            <option letter="d">It limited author rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The International Copyright Act protected foreign authors' rights, helping professionalize American publishing and ending the widespread piracy of European works.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="109">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the "Cross of Gold" speech?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It secured Bryan's nomination and defined the 1896 campaign</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">It united industrial workers</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported big business</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>William Jennings Bryan's "Cross of Gold" speech electrified the 1896 Democratic convention, secured his nomination, and defined the campaign's focus on free silver.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="110">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Interstate Commerce Commission?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To regulate railroad rates and practices</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote railroad expansion</option>
            <option letter="c">To prevent regulation</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect railroad profits</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Interstate Commerce Commission was created to regulate railroad rates and practices, though it initially lacked effective enforcement powers.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="111">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the Massachusetts Civil Service Law?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered merit-based government hiring at the state level</option>
            <option letter="b">It expanded patronage</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced efficiency</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased corruption</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Massachusetts Civil Service Law pioneered merit-based hiring for state government positions, serving as a model for other states and civil service reform.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="112">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of the Knights of Labor's cooperative movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To create worker-owned businesses as alternatives to capitalism</option>
            <option letter="b">To increase business profits</option>
            <option letter="c">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="d">To prevent unionization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Knights of Labor promoted worker-owned cooperative businesses as alternatives to capitalist enterprises, though most cooperatives ultimately failed.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="113">
        <prompt>What was the main argument of the Anti-Imperialist League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Imperialism violated American democratic principles</option>
            <option letter="b">Colonial expansion was too expensive</option>
            <option letter="c">The military was too weak for empire</option>
            <option letter="d">Other powers would object to U.S. expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Anti-Imperialist League, which included prominent figures like Mark Twain, argued that imperialism contradicted American values of self-determination and consent of the governed.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="114">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Gold Standard Act of 1900?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It officially placed the United States on the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="b">It established a bimetallic currency system</option>
            <option letter="c">It created the Federal Reserve System</option>
            <option letter="d">It eliminated paper currency</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Gold Standard Act of 1900 officially placed U.S. currency on the gold standard, ending the long debate over silver coinage and bimetallism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="115">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of grandfather clauses in Southern state constitutions?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To allow poor whites to vote while excluding African Americans</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect voting rights for all citizens</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase voter registration</option>
            <option letter="d">To simplify the voting process</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Grandfather clauses exempted those whose ancestors could vote before 1867 from literacy tests and poll taxes, effectively allowing poor whites to vote while excluding African Americans.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="116">
        <prompt>What was the main focus of Alfred T. Mahan's The Influence of Sea Power upon History?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The importance of naval power for national greatness</option>
            <option letter="b">The history of maritime trade</option>
            <option letter="c">Naval battle tactics</option>
            <option letter="d">Shipbuilding technology</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Mahan argued that control of the seas through a strong navy was essential for national power and imperial expansion, significantly influencing American naval and foreign policy.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="117">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the International Workers of the World?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To organize all workers into one revolutionary union</option>
            <option letter="b">To support craft unionism</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote capitalism</option>
            <option letter="d">To limit worker rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The IWW aimed to organize all workers into "One Big Union" to overthrow capitalism through industrial unionism and direct action.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="118">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Jacob Riis's photography?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It exposed urban poverty through visual documentation</option>
            <option letter="b">It celebrated city life</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted tourism</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported business</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Riis's photographs exposed urban poverty conditions to middle-class audiences, helping spark progressive reform efforts in cities.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="119">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of Frederick Winslow Taylor's ideas?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They increased industrial efficiency while reducing worker autonomy</option>
            <option letter="b">They improved working conditions</option>
            <option letter="c">They strengthened unions</option>
            <option letter="d">They increased wages</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Taylor's scientific management principles increased industrial efficiency but reduced worker autonomy by breaking tasks into standardized, measured components.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="120">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the American Anti-Imperialist League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To oppose U.S. territorial expansion overseas</option>
            <option letter="b">To support imperialism</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote colonization</option>
            <option letter="d">To expand military</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The American Anti-Imperialist League opposed U.S. territorial expansion, arguing it violated American democratic principles and traditional foreign policy.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="121">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It combined temperance reform with women's rights advocacy</option>
            <option letter="b">It focused solely on prohibiting alcohol</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed women's suffrage</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted religious education only</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Under Frances Willard's leadership, the WCTU combined its temperance mission with advocacy for women's suffrage and other social reforms, becoming the largest women's organization of its time.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="122">
        <prompt>What was the key provision of the Platt Amendment of 1901?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It gave the United States the right to intervene in Cuban affairs</option>
            <option letter="b">It granted Cuba full independence</option>
            <option letter="c">It established free trade with Cuba</option>
            <option letter="d">It protected Cuban sovereignty</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Platt Amendment made Cuba a U.S. protectorate by giving the United States the right to intervene in Cuban affairs and establish naval bases on the island.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="123">
        <prompt>What was the main outcome of the Philippine War (1899-1902)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The United States established control over the Philippines</option>
            <option letter="b">The Philippines gained immediate independence</option>
            <option letter="c">Spain retained control of the islands</option>
            <option letter="d">Japan acquired the territory</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Despite fierce Filipino resistance, the United States established control over the Philippines, resulting in American colonial rule that would last until 1946.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="124">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the National Association of Colored Women's formation in 1896?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It united black women's clubs nationwide for racial advancement</option>
            <option letter="b">It focused exclusively on suffrage rights</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted segregation policies</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed women's education</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The NACW united black women's clubs across the country, working for racial advancement through education, social services, and civil rights activism under the motto "Lifting as We Climb."</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="125">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To fight racial discrimination through legal action</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote segregation</option>
            <option letter="c">To support economic programs</option>
            <option letter="d">To organize boycotts</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The NAACP was founded to fight racial discrimination primarily through legal action and court cases, challenging segregation and disenfranchisement laws.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="126">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Frances Willard's leadership of the WCTU?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">She expanded its mission to include women's rights and social reform</option>
            <option letter="b">She focused solely on temperance</option>
            <option letter="c">She opposed women's suffrage</option>
            <option letter="d">She reduced its influence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Under Willard's leadership, the Woman's Christian Temperance Union expanded beyond temperance to advocate for women's rights and broader social reforms.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="127">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the McKinley Tariff of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It raised tariff rates and contributed to Republican electoral losses</option>
            <option letter="b">It lowered consumer prices</option>
            <option letter="c">It increased foreign trade</option>
            <option letter="d">It helped small businesses</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The McKinley Tariff raised rates to record levels, leading to higher consumer prices and contributing to Republican losses in the 1890 elections.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="128">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the American Protective Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To oppose Catholic influence in American society</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect immigrant rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote religious tolerance</option>
            <option letter="d">To support Catholic education</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The American Protective Association was an anti-Catholic organization that sought to limit Catholic influence in American society and restrict Catholic immigration.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="129">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of university settlement houses?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To apply social science to urban problems</option>
            <option letter="b">To provide student housing</option>
            <option letter="c">To conduct religious missions</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase property values</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>University settlement houses combined social services with social science research, as college-educated residents studied urban problems while helping immigrant communities.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="130">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Republican Party's "Full Dinner Pail" slogan?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It emphasized economic prosperity under Republican policies</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted food aid programs</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported labor unions</option>
            <option letter="d">It criticized business interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The "Full Dinner Pail" slogan symbolized economic prosperity under Republican leadership, appealing to workers' material interests in the 1900 election.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="131">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of urban political machines in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They provided services to immigrants in exchange for votes</option>
            <option letter="b">They eliminated corruption</option>
            <option letter="c">They reduced city services</option>
            <option letter="d">They opposed immigration</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Political machines provided jobs, services, and assistance to immigrant communities in exchange for political support, creating powerful urban political organizations.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="132">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Independent Treasury System?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To separate government finances from the banking system</option>
            <option letter="b">To support national banks</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase money supply</option>
            <option letter="d">To regulate Wall Street</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Independent Treasury System kept government funds separate from the banking system, but this separation often worsened financial crises by restricting money supply.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="133">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of William Randolph Hearst's journalism?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To increase circulation through sensationalized news</option>
            <option letter="b">To provide objective reporting</option>
            <option letter="c">To support peace with Spain</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote political reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Hearst pioneered yellow journalism, using sensationalized stories, dramatic headlines, and manufactured crises to increase newspaper circulation and influence public opinion.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="134">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the Sherman Silver Purchase Act's repeal?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It worsened the depression of 1893</option>
            <option letter="b">It improved the economy</option>
            <option letter="c">It helped silver miners</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased inflation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The repeal of the Sherman Silver Purchase Act in 1893 worsened the depression by further contracting the money supply and damaging silver mining communities.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="135">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Massachusetts Board of Railroad Commissioners?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered regulatory commission oversight of railroads</option>
            <option letter="b">It nationalized railroads</option>
            <option letter="c">It increased railroad rates</option>
            <option letter="d">It prevented regulation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Massachusetts Board pioneered the regulatory commission approach to railroad oversight, serving as a model for the Interstate Commerce Commission and other regulatory bodies.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="136">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of Jacob Riis's How the Other Half Lives?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To expose urban poverty through photojournalism</option>
            <option letter="b">To celebrate city life</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote immigration</option>
            <option letter="d">To support tenement owners</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Riis used photographs and journalism to expose the harsh conditions of urban poverty, particularly in New York's tenements, helping spark progressive reform efforts.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="137">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of the Catholic Total Abstinence Union?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote temperance within the Catholic community</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose Protestant reform</option>
            <option letter="c">To support saloon culture</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase alcohol sales</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Catholic Total Abstinence Union worked to promote temperance within the Catholic community while countering anti-Catholic prejudice in the broader temperance movement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="138">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Northern Securities case?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established the government's power to break up railroad monopolies</option>
            <option letter="b">It protected business combinations</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced regulation</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported trusts</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court's decision in Northern Securities Co. v. United States established the government's power to break up railroad monopolies under the Sherman Antitrust Act.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="139">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Cuban Reciprocity Treaty?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To maintain U.S. economic control over Cuba</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote Cuban independence</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce trade barriers</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect Cuban industry</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Cuban Reciprocity Treaty maintained U.S. economic control over Cuba through preferential trade arrangements that made Cuba dependent on the U.S. market.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="140">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the Populist Party's fusion with Democrats?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It led to the decline of the independent Populist movement</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened both parties</option>
            <option letter="c">It achieved reform goals</option>
            <option letter="d">It united farmers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Populists' fusion with Democrats in 1896 led to the decline of the independent Populist movement as it lost its distinctive identity and failed to achieve its goals.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="141">
        <prompt>What was the immediate cause of the 1893 economic depression?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The failure of the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad</option>
            <option letter="b">The passage of the Sherman Silver Purchase Act</option>
            <option letter="c">A decline in agricultural exports</option>
            <option letter="d">The collapse of the stock market</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Panic of 1893 was triggered by the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad declaring bankruptcy, leading to a domino effect of bank failures and business closures.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="142">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Pullman Strike of 1894?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It marked the first use of federal troops to break a strike</option>
            <option letter="b">It led to the creation of Labor Day as a federal holiday</option>
            <option letter="c">It resulted in the formation of the AFL</option>
            <option letter="d">It ended in a victory for the workers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>President Cleveland's use of federal troops to break the Pullman Strike set a precedent for federal intervention in labor disputes and demonstrated the government's alignment with business interests.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="143">
        <prompt>What was the main argument in Booker T. Washington's Atlanta Compromise speech?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">African Americans should focus on economic self-reliance before political rights</option>
            <option letter="b">Immediate political equality was necessary for racial progress</option>
            <option letter="c">The federal government should enforce civil rights laws</option>
            <option letter="d">Social integration should be the primary goal</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Washington advocated for African Americans to focus on economic self-improvement and industrial education rather than immediate social and political equality, a position that became known as the Atlanta Compromise.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="144">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the USS Maine explosion in 1898?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It provided the immediate justification for war with Spain</option>
            <option letter="b">It demonstrated the need for naval reform</option>
            <option letter="c">It led to improved ship construction methods</option>
            <option letter="d">It caused a diplomatic crisis with Britain</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The explosion of the USS Maine in Havana harbor, though never conclusively linked to Spain, provided the immediate catalyst for the Spanish-American War after yellow journalism inflamed public opinion.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="145">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Red Record?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To document and publicize lynching in the South</option>
            <option letter="b">To record business transactions</option>
            <option letter="c">To track voter registration</option>
            <option letter="d">To list property ownership</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Ida B. Wells's The Red Record documented and publicized the practice of lynching in the South, helping to mobilize anti-lynching activism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="146">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Minneapolis flour milling industry?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated the efficiency of industrial consolidation</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported small businesses</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced grain production</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased competition</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Minneapolis flour milling industry demonstrated how industrial consolidation and technological innovation could increase efficiency and market control.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="147">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the National Guard's role in labor disputes?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It strengthened business control over labor relations</option>
            <option letter="b">It protected worker rights</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted negotiations</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Guard's frequent use against strikers strengthened business control over labor relations by providing military force to break strikes.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="148">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Immigration Restriction League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect immigrant rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To assist new immigrants</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote cultural diversity</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Immigration Restriction League worked to limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe, arguing that these immigrants were racially and culturally inferior.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="149">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the American Federation of Labor's "pure and simple" unionism?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To focus exclusively on workplace improvements for skilled workers</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote socialist revolution</option>
            <option letter="c">To organize all workers</option>
            <option letter="d">To support political parties</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The AFL under Gompers pursued "pure and simple" unionism, focusing on immediate workplace improvements for skilled workers rather than broader social or political reform.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="150">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Liliuokalani's proposed constitution?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It prompted American planters to overthrow the Hawaiian monarchy</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened Hawaiian independence</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected American interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted democracy</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Queen Liliuokalani's attempt to strengthen native Hawaiian power through a new constitution prompted American planters to overthrow her with U.S. military support.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="151">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the national banking system in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It created an inelastic currency that worsened economic problems</option>
            <option letter="b">It provided stable monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="c">It prevented bank failures</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased money supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The national banking system created an inelastic currency that couldn't expand to meet seasonal demands, contributing to financial instability and economic problems.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="152">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Social Gospel movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To apply Christian principles to social problems</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote individual salvation</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose immigration</option>
            <option letter="d">To support laissez-faire economics</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Social Gospel movement sought to apply Christian principles to address social problems like poverty, inequality, and urban conditions, promoting social reform through religious activism.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="153">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Farmers' Alliance newspaper network?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To spread Alliance ideas and organize rural communities</option>
            <option letter="b">To support major newspapers</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose reform movements</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote urban interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Alliance newspaper network spread reform ideas and helped organize rural communities, creating a communications system independent of mainstream media.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="154">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Atlanta Exposition Address?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It presented Booker T. Washington's accommodationist approach</option>
            <option letter="b">It demanded immediate equality</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted political activism</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed segregation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Washington's Atlanta Exposition Address presented his accommodationist approach to race relations, emphasizing economic self-help over political and social equality.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="155">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Sherman Silver Purchase Act?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It failed to solve the currency problem and worsened the depression</option>
            <option letter="b">It stabilized the economy</option>
            <option letter="c">It helped silver miners</option>
            <option letter="d">It prevented the panic</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Sherman Silver Purchase Act failed to solve the currency problem and contributed to the Panic of 1893 by depleting government gold reserves.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="156">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Bureau of Immigration?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To regulate and restrict immigration</option>
            <option letter="b">To assist immigrants</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote immigration</option>
            <option letter="d">To provide citizenship</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Bureau of Immigration was established to regulate and restrict immigration, implementing new laws that excluded certain groups and established inspection procedures.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="157">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the election of 1896 on American politics?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established Republican dominance for a generation</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened the Populist Party</option>
            <option letter="c">It led to progressive reforms</option>
            <option letter="d">It united regional interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>McKinley's victory in 1896 established Republican political dominance that would last for most of the next thirty-six years, ending the period of close presidential elections.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="158">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Anti-Saloon League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To achieve national prohibition through focused political action</option>
            <option letter="b">To regulate alcohol sales</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote moderate drinking</option>
            <option letter="d">To support local taverns</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Anti-Saloon League focused single-mindedly on achieving national prohibition through political pressure and organizing, becoming one of the most effective reform groups.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="159">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Omaha Platform of 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It presented the Populist Party's comprehensive reform agenda</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed government regulation</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted industrial interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Omaha Platform outlined the Populist Party's reform agenda, including free silver, government ownership of railroads, and other measures to help farmers and workers.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="160">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Venezuela Boundary Dispute intervention?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To assert U.S. dominance in the Western Hemisphere</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect Venezuelan independence</option>
            <option letter="c">To support British claims</option>
            <option letter="d">To acquire territory</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Cleveland's intervention in the Venezuela-British Guiana boundary dispute forcefully reasserted the Monroe Doctrine and U.S. dominance in the Western Hemisphere.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="161">
        <prompt>What was the key argument in Plessy v. Ferguson (1896)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Separate facilities were constitutional if they were equal</option>
            <option letter="b">Segregation violated the 14th Amendment</option>
            <option letter="c">States could not regulate interstate commerce</option>
            <option letter="d">Civil rights legislation was unconstitutional</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court ruled that segregation was constitutional as long as facilities were "separate but equal," establishing the legal basis for Jim Crow laws across the South.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="162">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Immigration Restriction League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote Asian immigration</option>
            <option letter="c">To expand immigration quotas</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect immigrant rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Founded in 1894, the Immigration Restriction League sought to limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe, arguing that these immigrants were racially and culturally inferior to earlier immigrants.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="163">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Open Door Policy in China?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To ensure equal trading opportunities for all nations in China</option>
            <option letter="b">To establish exclusive American trading rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote Chinese independence</option>
            <option letter="d">To limit Japanese influence in Asia</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Secretary of State John Hay's Open Door Policy sought to ensure that all nations would have equal trading opportunities in China, preventing any single power from monopolizing Chinese markets.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="164">
        <prompt>What was the primary cause of Coxey's Army march in 1894?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To protest unemployment and demand public works programs</option>
            <option letter="b">To support the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose immigration restrictions</option>
            <option letter="d">To advocate for women's suffrage</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Jacob Coxey led unemployed workers to Washington D.C. to demand government-funded public works programs during the economic depression, representing one of the first protest marches on Washington.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="165">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Homestead Strike of 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated the effectiveness of private security forces against unions</option>
            <option letter="b">It resulted in better working conditions for steel workers</option>
            <option letter="c">It led to the creation of new labor laws</option>
            <option letter="d">It strengthened the power of labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The defeat of the Homestead Strike by Pinkerton agents and the state militia demonstrated the power of corporations and their ability to use private security forces to break unions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="166">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of the Populist Party platform in 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The free and unlimited coinage of silver at a 16:1 ratio with gold</option>
            <option letter="b">The abolition of the national banking system</option>
            <option letter="c">The establishment of a federal income tax</option>
            <option letter="d">The nationalization of railroads</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Populists' primary demand was for free silver coinage at a 16:1 ratio with gold, which they believed would help farmers by causing inflation and making it easier to pay off debts.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="167">
        <prompt>What role did yellow journalism play in the Spanish-American War?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It inflamed public opinion against Spain through sensationalized stories</option>
            <option letter="b">It provided accurate war reporting</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed American intervention</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported Spanish colonial policies</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Newspapers like Hearst's and Pulitzer's used sensationalized and often exaggerated stories about Spanish atrocities in Cuba to build public support for war with Spain.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="168">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Hawaiian annexation in 1898?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To secure a strategic naval base in the Pacific</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect native Hawaiian rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To support sugar plantation workers</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote Hawaiian independence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The United States annexed Hawaii primarily to secure Pearl Harbor as a strategic naval base in the Pacific, supporting American military and commercial interests in Asia.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="169">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of Frederick Jackson Turner's Frontier Thesis?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To explain American democracy through frontier expansion</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose westward expansion</option>
            <option letter="c">To protect Native Americans</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote urbanization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Turner argued that the American frontier experience shaped American democracy and character, presenting his influential thesis at the 1893 Columbian Exposition.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="170">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Farmers' Alliances?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They organized farmers and led to the Populist movement</option>
            <option letter="b">They supported big business</option>
            <option letter="c">They opposed political action</option>
            <option letter="d">They promoted industrialization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Farmers' Alliances organized farmers for economic cooperation and education, laying the groundwork for the Populist movement of the 1890s.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="171">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of Edward Bellamy's Looking Backward?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It popularized nationalist clubs and socialist ideas</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported laissez-faire capitalism</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted conservative values</option>
            <option letter="d">It criticized reform movements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Bellamy's utopian novel popularized socialist ideas and led to the formation of nationalist clubs dedicated to achieving his vision of a cooperative society.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="172">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Naval Act of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To build a modern American naval fleet</option>
            <option letter="b">To reduce military spending</option>
            <option letter="c">To maintain isolation</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect coastal waters only</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Naval Act of 1890 authorized the construction of modern battleships, beginning the transformation of the U.S. Navy into a world-class naval power.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="173">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of Alice Fletcher's work with Native Americans?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">She implemented the Dawes Act's land allotment program</option>
            <option letter="b">She protected tribal lands</option>
            <option letter="c">She preserved native culture</option>
            <option letter="d">She opposed assimilation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>As a special agent, Fletcher implemented the Dawes Act's land allotment program, believing that private property would help Native Americans assimilate into white society.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="174">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the People's Party Convention of 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established the first national third-party platform</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed labor reform</option>
            <option letter="d">It united with Democrats</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The 1892 People's Party Convention created the first comprehensive third-party platform, demanding monetary reform, government ownership of railroads, and other reforms.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="175">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Municipal League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote urban reform and efficient city government</option>
            <option letter="b">To support political machines</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce city services</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase corruption</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Municipal League worked to promote urban reform and efficient city government through research, education, and model legislation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="176">
        <prompt>What was the primary impact of the Columbian Exposition of 1893?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It showcased American progress and cultural achievement</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted racial equality</option>
            <option letter="c">It criticized industrialization</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Chicago World's Fair celebrated American progress and cultural achievements, though it largely excluded African Americans and presented a sanitized view of society.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="177">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Consumers League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To improve working conditions through consumer pressure</option>
            <option letter="b">To lower product prices</option>
            <option letter="c">To support businesses</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Consumers League used consumer pressure and product labeling to improve working conditions and end child labor in manufacturing.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="178">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Billion Dollar Congress?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It set new records for government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">It reduced federal expenses</option>
            <option letter="c">It balanced the budget</option>
            <option letter="d">It eliminated programs</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The 51st Congress earned its nickname by setting new records for government spending, leading to public criticism and Republican electoral losses.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="179">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of Eugene V. Debs's imprisonment?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It transformed him into a socialist leader</option>
            <option letter="b">It ended labor activism</option>
            <option letter="c">It strengthened unions</option>
            <option letter="d">It reduced strikes</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Debs's imprisonment after the Pullman Strike led to his conversion to socialism and transformation into America's leading socialist political figure.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="180">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Farmers' Institutes?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To provide agricultural education and community organizing</option>
            <option letter="b">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose reform</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote urbanization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Farmers' Institutes provided agricultural education and served as centers for community organizing, helping spread agricultural knowledge and reform ideas.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="181">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Populist Omaha Platform of 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To present a comprehensive program of economic and political reform</option>
            <option letter="b">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote conservatism</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Omaha Platform presented the Populists' comprehensive reform program, including government ownership of railroads, free silver, and direct election of senators.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="182">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Hull House Maps and Papers?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It documented urban poverty through social science research</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted business interests</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported segregation</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Hull House Maps and Papers documented urban poverty conditions through pioneering social science research, influencing progressive reform efforts.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="183">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Cuban Reconcentration Policy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It increased American support for war with Spain</option>
            <option letter="b">It stabilized Cuba</option>
            <option letter="c">It helped Cuban civilians</option>
            <option letter="d">It reduced conflict</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Spain's brutal reconcentration policy, which led to widespread civilian deaths, increased American public support for intervention in Cuba.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="184">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the National Association of Manufacturers?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote business interests and oppose labor unions</option>
            <option letter="b">To support worker rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase regulation</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Association of Manufacturers formed to promote business interests, oppose labor unions, and advocate for high tariffs and gold standard policies.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="185">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the White City at the World's Columbian Exposition?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To showcase American cultural and technological achievement</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote racial equality</option>
            <option letter="c">To celebrate diversity</option>
            <option letter="d">To criticize urbanization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The White City showcased American cultural and technological achievements while promoting a vision of civic order and classical beauty that influenced urban planning.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="186">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Jane Addams's Democracy and Social Ethics?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It provided a theoretical foundation for progressive reform</option>
            <option letter="b">It opposed social change</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported business interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted traditional values</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Addams's book provided a theoretical foundation for progressive reform by arguing that democracy required active social engagement and ethical responsibility.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="187">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the National Cordage Company's failure?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It helped trigger the Panic of 1893</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened the economy</option>
            <option letter="c">It improved business practices</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported small businesses</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Cordage Company's collapse in May 1893 helped trigger the Panic of 1893, demonstrating the dangers of overcapitalization and speculation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="188">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Silver Democrats?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To secure free silver coinage at a 16:1 ratio</option>
            <option letter="b">To maintain the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce inflation</option>
            <option letter="d">To support national banks</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Silver Democrats fought for the free coinage of silver at a 16:1 ratio with gold, believing it would increase the money supply and help debtors.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="189">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Anti-Trust League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote enforcement of the Sherman Anti-Trust Act</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect monopolies</option>
            <option letter="c">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose regulation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Anti-Trust League worked to promote enforcement of the Sherman Anti-Trust Act and raise public awareness about the dangers of monopolies.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="190">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Battle of Adwa?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated resistance to European imperialism</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported colonization</option>
            <option letter="c">It expanded American power</option>
            <option letter="d">It united European nations</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Ethiopia's victory over Italy at Adwa in 1896 demonstrated successful resistance to European imperialism and influenced anti-imperialist thought.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="191">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Agricultural Wheel movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It organized farmers for economic and political action</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported big business</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed reform</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted industrialization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Agricultural Wheel organized farmers for cooperative economic action and political reform, contributing to the broader agrarian protest movement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="192">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Good Roads Movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To improve rural transportation infrastructure</option>
            <option letter="b">To limit road construction</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose government spending</option>
            <option letter="d">To support railroads</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Good Roads Movement advocated for improved rural roads and highways, uniting farmers, cyclists, and urban reformers in support of better transportation infrastructure.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="193">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Baptist Convention?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To unite African American Baptists for religious and social action</option>
            <option letter="b">To support segregation</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose civil rights</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote integration</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Baptist Convention united African American Baptists for religious worship and social action, becoming the largest African American religious organization.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="194">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Nicaraguan Canal proposal?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated growing American interest in Central America</option>
            <option letter="b">It reduced U.S. influence</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported European control</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Nicaraguan Canal proposal demonstrated growing American interest in controlling Central American transportation routes, though Panama was ultimately chosen.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="195">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Panic of 1893 on labor unions?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It weakened union membership and bargaining power</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened unions</option>
            <option letter="c">It improved working conditions</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased wages</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Panic of 1893 severely weakened labor unions as unemployment rose and workers became more concerned with survival than organization.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="196">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the National Direct Legislation League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote initiative and referendum in state government</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose democracy</option>
            <option letter="c">To support political machines</option>
            <option letter="d">To limit voting rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Direct Legislation League worked to promote initiative and referendum procedures in state governments to increase direct democracy.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>