<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="37">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Alaska purchase in 1867?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To secure strategic territory and natural resources</option>
            <option letter="b">To establish new farming settlements</option>
            <option letter="c">To prevent British expansion</option>
            <option letter="d">To create Native American reservations</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Secretary of State William Seward pursued the Alaska purchase to secure strategic territory and natural resources, though critics called it "Seward's Folly" until the discovery of gold in the late 1890s.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="38">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the separate but equal doctrine?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It provided legal justification for systematic segregation</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted racial integration</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected minority rights</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased educational funding</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The separate but equal doctrine, established by Plessy v. Ferguson, provided legal justification for systematic racial segregation across the South and beyond.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="39">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of yellow journalism in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It helped create public support for the Spanish-American War</option>
            <option letter="b">It improved journalistic accuracy</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced newspaper circulation</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted international peace</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Yellow journalism, particularly by Hearst and Pulitzer's newspapers, used sensationalized stories about Spanish atrocities to build public support for war with Spain.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="40">
        <prompt>What was the primary motivation for U.S. imperialism in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Economic expansion and strategic military interests</option>
            <option letter="b">Spreading democracy</option>
            <option letter="c">Humanitarian concerns</option>
            <option letter="d">Cultural exchange</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>U.S. imperialism was primarily motivated by the desire for new markets, strategic military bases, and the belief that national greatness required overseas expansion.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
