<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="73">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the American Protective Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To oppose Catholic influence in American society</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect immigrant rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote religious tolerance</option>
            <option letter="d">To support Catholic education</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The American Protective Association was an anti-Catholic organization that claimed Catholics were plotting to take over America and opposed Catholic immigration.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="74">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Wilson-Gorman Tariff of 1894?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To reduce tariff rates and implement an income tax</option>
            <option letter="b">To increase protective tariffs</option>
            <option letter="c">To eliminate all tariffs</option>
            <option letter="d">To fund internal improvements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Wilson-Gorman Tariff modestly reduced tariff rates and included a federal income tax provision, though the Supreme Court later ruled the income tax unconstitutional.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="75">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Ida B. Wells's anti-lynching campaign?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It exposed lynching as a tool of racial terrorism</option>
            <option letter="b">It ended lynching immediately</option>
            <option letter="c">It secured federal legislation</option>
            <option letter="d">It united white and black southerners</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Wells's investigative journalism and campaigns exposed lynching as a tool of racial terrorism rather than punishment for crime, bringing international attention to the practice.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="76">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Columbian Exposition of 1893?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It showcased American industrial and technological progress</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted racial equality</option>
            <option letter="c">It criticized industrialization</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Chicago World's Fair celebrated American industrial and technological achievements, promoting a vision of progress while largely excluding African American contributions.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
