<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="5">
        <prompt>What was the key argument in Plessy v. Ferguson (1896)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Separate facilities were constitutional if they were equal</option>
            <option letter="b">Segregation violated the 14th Amendment</option>
            <option letter="c">States could not regulate interstate commerce</option>
            <option letter="d">Civil rights legislation was unconstitutional</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court ruled that segregation was constitutional as long as facilities were "separate but equal," establishing the legal basis for Jim Crow laws across the South.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="6">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Immigration Restriction League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote Asian immigration</option>
            <option letter="c">To expand immigration quotas</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect immigrant rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Founded in 1894, the Immigration Restriction League sought to limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe, arguing that these immigrants were racially and culturally inferior to earlier immigrants.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="7">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Open Door Policy in China?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To ensure equal trading opportunities for all nations in China</option>
            <option letter="b">To establish exclusive American trading rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote Chinese independence</option>
            <option letter="d">To limit Japanese influence in Asia</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Secretary of State John Hay's Open Door Policy sought to ensure that all nations would have equal trading opportunities in China, preventing any single power from monopolizing Chinese markets.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="8">
        <prompt>What was the primary cause of Coxey's Army march in 1894?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To protest unemployment and demand public works programs</option>
            <option letter="b">To support the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose immigration restrictions</option>
            <option letter="d">To advocate for women's suffrage</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Jacob Coxey led unemployed workers to Washington D.C. to demand government-funded public works programs during the economic depression, representing one of the first protest marches on Washington.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
