<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="81">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the election of 1896 on American politics?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established Republican dominance for a generation</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened the Populist Party</option>
            <option letter="c">It led to progressive reforms</option>
            <option letter="d">It united regional interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>McKinley's victory in 1896 established Republican political dominance that would last for most of the next thirty-six years, ending the period of close presidential elections.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="82">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Anti-Saloon League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To achieve national prohibition through focused political action</option>
            <option letter="b">To regulate alcohol sales</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote moderate drinking</option>
            <option letter="d">To support local taverns</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Anti-Saloon League focused single-mindedly on achieving national prohibition through political pressure and organizing, becoming one of the most effective reform groups.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="83">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Omaha Platform of 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It presented the Populist Party's comprehensive reform agenda</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed government regulation</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted industrial interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Omaha Platform outlined the Populist Party's reform agenda, including free silver, government ownership of railroads, and other measures to help farmers and workers.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="84">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Venezuela Boundary Dispute intervention?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To assert U.S. dominance in the Western Hemisphere</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect Venezuelan independence</option>
            <option letter="c">To support British claims</option>
            <option letter="d">To acquire territory</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Cleveland's intervention in the Venezuela-British Guiana boundary dispute forcefully reasserted the Monroe Doctrine and U.S. dominance in the Western Hemisphere.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
