<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="97">
        <prompt>What was the main argument of Josiah Strong's Our Country?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Anglo-Saxons had a duty to spread civilization worldwide</option>
            <option letter="b">America should remain isolated</option>
            <option letter="c">Immigration should be encouraged</option>
            <option letter="d">Cultural diversity was beneficial</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Strong's influential book argued that Anglo-Saxons had a divine mission to spread their civilization worldwide, helping justify American imperialism and expansion.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="98">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of settlement houses?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To provide social services and education to urban immigrants</option>
            <option letter="b">To restrict immigration</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote segregation</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase property values</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Settlement houses provided education, social services, and cultural programs to urban immigrants while promoting social reform through resident workers' activism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="99">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of William McKinley's campaign strategy in 1896?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered modern campaign techniques and corporate fundraising</option>
            <option letter="b">It reduced campaign spending</option>
            <option letter="c">It alienated business interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported free silver</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>McKinley's campaign pioneered modern techniques including unprecedented corporate fundraising, sophisticated voter targeting, and extensive publicity materials.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="100">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Sewing Machine Trust?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated how patent pools could create monopolies</option>
            <option letter="b">It improved working conditions</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced product prices</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted competition</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Sewing Machine Trust showed how companies could use patent pools to create monopolies and control markets, becoming a model for other industries.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
