<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="101">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of university settlement houses?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To apply social science to urban problems</option>
            <option letter="b">To provide student housing</option>
            <option letter="c">To conduct religious missions</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase property values</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>University settlement houses combined social services with social science research, as college-educated residents studied urban problems while helping immigrant communities.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="102">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Republican Party's "Full Dinner Pail" slogan?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It emphasized economic prosperity under Republican policies</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted food aid programs</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported labor unions</option>
            <option letter="d">It criticized business interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The "Full Dinner Pail" slogan symbolized economic prosperity under Republican leadership, appealing to workers' material interests in the 1900 election.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="103">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of urban political machines in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They provided services to immigrants in exchange for votes</option>
            <option letter="b">They eliminated corruption</option>
            <option letter="c">They reduced city services</option>
            <option letter="d">They opposed immigration</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Political machines provided jobs, services, and assistance to immigrant communities in exchange for political support, creating powerful urban political organizations.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="104">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Independent Treasury System?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To separate government finances from the banking system</option>
            <option letter="b">To support national banks</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase money supply</option>
            <option letter="d">To regulate Wall Street</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Independent Treasury System kept government funds separate from the banking system, but this separation often worsened financial crises by restricting money supply.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
