<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="105">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of Joseph Pulitzer's journalism?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered mass-circulation newspapers and sensationalism</option>
            <option letter="b">It focused on objective reporting</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed yellow journalism</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported Spanish policies</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Pulitzer pioneered mass-circulation newspapers through sensationalism, human interest stories, and crusading journalism, though he was generally more responsible than Hearst.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="106">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Bland-Allison Act of 1878?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It required limited silver purchases but didn't satisfy silver advocates</option>
            <option letter="b">It established free silver coinage</option>
            <option letter="c">It ended silver purchases</option>
            <option letter="d">It stabilized currency value</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Bland-Allison Act required the Treasury to purchase some silver, but the amount was too limited to satisfy silver advocates or significantly affect the money supply.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="107">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Dawes Severalty Act?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To break up tribal lands and force Native American assimilation</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect tribal sovereignty</option>
            <option letter="c">To expand Indian reservations</option>
            <option letter="d">To preserve native culture</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Dawes Act aimed to break up tribal lands into individual allotments and force Native Americans to adopt European-American farming practices and cultural values.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="108">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the International Copyright Act of 1891?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It protected foreign authors' rights and professionalized American publishing</option>
            <option letter="b">It restricted book publication</option>
            <option letter="c">It increased book prices</option>
            <option letter="d">It limited author rights</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The International Copyright Act protected foreign authors' rights, helping professionalize American publishing and ending the widespread piracy of European works.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
