<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="125">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To fight racial discrimination through legal action</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote segregation</option>
            <option letter="c">To support economic programs</option>
            <option letter="d">To organize boycotts</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The NAACP was founded to fight racial discrimination primarily through legal action and court cases, challenging segregation and disenfranchisement laws.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="126">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Frances Willard's leadership of the WCTU?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">She expanded its mission to include women's rights and social reform</option>
            <option letter="b">She focused solely on temperance</option>
            <option letter="c">She opposed women's suffrage</option>
            <option letter="d">She reduced its influence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Under Willard's leadership, the Woman's Christian Temperance Union expanded beyond temperance to advocate for women's rights and broader social reforms.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="127">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the McKinley Tariff of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It raised tariff rates and contributed to Republican electoral losses</option>
            <option letter="b">It lowered consumer prices</option>
            <option letter="c">It increased foreign trade</option>
            <option letter="d">It helped small businesses</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The McKinley Tariff raised rates to record levels, leading to higher consumer prices and contributing to Republican losses in the 1890 elections.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="128">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the American Protective Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To oppose Catholic influence in American society</option>
            <option letter="b">To protect immigrant rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote religious tolerance</option>
            <option letter="d">To support Catholic education</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The American Protective Association was an anti-Catholic organization that sought to limit Catholic influence in American society and restrict Catholic immigration.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
