<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="157">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the White City at the World's Columbian Exposition?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To showcase American cultural and technological achievement</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote racial equality</option>
            <option letter="c">To celebrate diversity</option>
            <option letter="d">To criticize urbanization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The White City showcased American cultural and technological achievements while promoting a vision of civic order and classical beauty that influenced urban planning.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="158">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Jane Addams's Democracy and Social Ethics?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It provided a theoretical foundation for progressive reform</option>
            <option letter="b">It opposed social change</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported business interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted traditional values</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Addams's book provided a theoretical foundation for progressive reform by arguing that democracy required active social engagement and ethical responsibility.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="159">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the National Cordage Company's failure?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It helped trigger the Panic of 1893</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened the economy</option>
            <option letter="c">It improved business practices</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported small businesses</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Cordage Company's collapse in May 1893 helped trigger the Panic of 1893, demonstrating the dangers of overcapitalization and speculation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="160">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Silver Democrats?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To secure free silver coinage at a 16:1 ratio</option>
            <option letter="b">To maintain the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce inflation</option>
            <option letter="d">To support national banks</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Silver Democrats fought for the free coinage of silver at a 16:1 ratio with gold, believing it would increase the money supply and help debtors.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
