<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="25">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of William McKinley's front porch campaign in 1896?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To project a conservative, dignified image in contrast to Bryan</option>
            <option letter="b">To save campaign travel expenses</option>
            <option letter="c">To avoid public speaking</option>
            <option letter="d">To focus solely on Ohio voters</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>McKinley's front porch campaign strategy allowed him to project a dignified, conservative image while Bryan's whistle-stop touring appeared radical and unstable to many voters.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="26">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Civil Rights Cases decision of 1883?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To limit federal power to protect civil rights</option>
            <option letter="b">To expand civil rights protections</option>
            <option letter="c">To enforce the 14th Amendment</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote racial equality</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court's decision in the Civil Rights Cases severely limited federal power to protect civil rights by ruling that the 14th Amendment only applied to state, not private, actions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="27">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the American Federation of Labor's founding?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established craft unionism as the dominant labor organization model</option>
            <option letter="b">It united all workers regardless of skill</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted socialist ideology</option>
            <option letter="d">It focused on unskilled laborers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The AFL, under Samuel Gompers, established craft unionism focused on skilled workers as the dominant form of labor organization, rejecting both industrial unionism and political radicalism.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="28">
        <prompt>What was the main result of the Treaty of Paris of 1898?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Spain ceded control of Cuba, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Philippines</option>
            <option letter="b">The U.S. gained control of Hawaii</option>
            <option letter="c">Spain retained control of Cuba</option>
            <option letter="d">The Philippines gained independence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Treaty of Paris ending the Spanish-American War resulted in Spain ceding control of Cuba, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Philippines to the United States for $20 million.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
