<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="29">
        <prompt>What was the primary significance of the Insular Cases (1901)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They established that the Constitution did not fully apply to U.S. territories</option>
            <option letter="b">They granted full citizenship to territorial residents</option>
            <option letter="c">They required territorial independence</option>
            <option letter="d">They prohibited U.S. expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court's decisions in the Insular Cases established that the Constitution did not automatically extend in full to U.S. territories, creating the concept of "unincorporated territories."</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="30">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of lynching in the 1890s South?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To maintain white supremacy through racial terrorism</option>
            <option letter="b">To enforce criminal justice</option>
            <option letter="c">To prevent property crimes</option>
            <option letter="d">To resolve personal disputes</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Lynching served as a form of racial terrorism designed to maintain white supremacy by intimidating African Americans and enforcing social and economic subordination.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="31">
        <prompt>What was the key feature of the "New South" movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It promoted industrialization while maintaining racial segregation</option>
            <option letter="b">It advocated for civil rights reform</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed economic development</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported agricultural reform only</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The New South movement promoted industrial development and economic modernization while maintaining the racial hierarchy through segregation and disfranchisement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="32">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of the Chinese Exclusion Act's extension in 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It made Chinese exclusion permanent and required registration</option>
            <option letter="b">It allowed increased Chinese immigration</option>
            <option letter="c">It granted citizenship to Chinese residents</option>
            <option letter="d">It improved conditions for Chinese Americans</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Geary Act of 1892 extended the Chinese Exclusion Act for another ten years and required all Chinese residents to register and obtain certificates of residence or face deportation.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
