<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="33">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the National American Woman Suffrage Association?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To win women's voting rights through state-by-state campaigns</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote prohibition</option>
            <option letter="c">To secure equal pay for women</option>
            <option letter="d">To reform marriage laws</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>NAWSA, formed in 1890, focused primarily on achieving women's suffrage through state-by-state campaigns rather than pursuing a federal amendment or broader women's rights issues.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="34">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Kansas Exodus of 1879-1880?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It demonstrated African Americans' willingness to leave the South for freedom</option>
            <option letter="b">It led to improved conditions in the South</option>
            <option letter="c">It resulted in significant land grants</option>
            <option letter="d">It ended racial violence in Kansas</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Exodus of thousands of African Americans to Kansas showed their determination to escape Southern oppression, though many faced hardship in their new homes.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="35">
        <prompt>What was the significance of William Jennings Bryan's "Cross of Gold" speech?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It united the Democratic and Populist parties behind free silver</option>
            <option letter="b">It won him the presidency</option>
            <option letter="c">It supported the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="d">It advocated for banking reform</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Bryan's dramatic speech at the 1896 Democratic Convention united the Democratic and Populist parties behind the free silver cause, though he ultimately lost the election.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="36">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of state constitutional disfranchisement provisions?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To legally eliminate African American voting while avoiding federal intervention</option>
            <option letter="b">To prevent voter fraud</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase voter participation</option>
            <option letter="d">To simplify voting procedures</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Southern states used various constitutional provisions like literacy tests and poll taxes to legally eliminate African American voting rights while avoiding direct federal intervention.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
