<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz><question number="1">
        <prompt>What explains why the Marginal Propensity to Consume (MPC) plus the Marginal Propensity to Save (MPS) must equal 1?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Government regulations require it</option>
            <option letter="b">The Fed maintains this ratio</option>
            <option letter="c">Each additional dollar must be either spent or saved</option>
            <option letter="d">Banks ensure this balance through lending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>MPC + MPS = 1 because each additional dollar of income must be either consumed (spent) or saved. Since these are the only two options for using additional income, their marginal propensities must sum to 100% or 1. This is a fundamental accounting identity.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="2">
        <prompt>When government spending increases by $100 billion and the MPC is 0.8, what is the total change in GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$100 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">$400 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$500 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$800 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>With an MPC of 0.8, the spending multiplier is 1/(1-0.8) = 5. When government spending increases by $100 billion, the total change in GDP is $100 billion × 5 = $500 billion, as the initial spending creates multiple rounds of additional spending.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="3">
        <prompt>When the Fed engages in expansionary monetary policy, what happens to bank reserves and the money supply?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Reserves decrease, money supply decreases</option>
            <option letter="b">Reserves increase, money supply increases</option>
            <option letter="c">Reserves increase, money supply decreases</option>
            <option letter="d">Reserves decrease, money supply increases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>During expansionary monetary policy, the Fed typically buys government securities, which increases bank reserves. These additional reserves allow banks to make more loans through the money multiplier process, leading to an increase in the money supply in the economy.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="4">
        <prompt>Why might open market operations be preferred over changing the discount rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Open market operations are more gradual</option>
            <option letter="b">Open market operations require Congressional approval</option>
            <option letter="c">Open market operations allow for more precise control of money supply</option>
            <option letter="d">Open market operations take longer to implement</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Open market operations are preferred because they allow the Fed to make small, precise adjustments to the money supply through buying or selling securities. Changes can be made quickly, in varying amounts, and can be easily reversed if needed, unlike discount rate changes which are more dramatic signals.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="5">
        <prompt>What happens to the loanable funds market when household saving rates increase?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Supply shifts right, interest rates fall, quantity of loans increases</option>
            <option letter="b">Supply shifts left, interest rates rise, quantity of loans decreases</option>
            <option letter="c">Demand shifts right, interest rates rise, quantity of loans increases</option>
            <option letter="d">Demand shifts left, interest rates fall, quantity of loans decreases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>When households save more, the supply of loanable funds increases (shifts right) at every interest rate. This increased supply leads to lower equilibrium interest rates and a larger quantity of loans in the market as more funds are available for lending.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="6">
        <prompt>A bank has $200,000 in deposits and an 8% required reserve ratio. If it's currently holding $20,000 in reserves, what is its excess reserve ratio?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">2%</option>
            <option letter="b">4%</option>
            <option letter="c">6%</option>
            <option letter="d">8%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Required reserves = 8% × $200,000 = $16,000. Excess reserves = Actual reserves - Required reserves = $20,000 - $16,000 = $4,000. Excess reserve ratio = Excess reserves/Deposits = $4,000/$200,000 = 0.02 = 2%. This represents additional reserves beyond the requirement.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="7">
        <prompt>When the Fed reduces the money supply through open market operations, what is the sequence of effects?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money supply ↓, interest rates ↑, investment ↑, AD ↑</option>
            <option letter="b">Money supply ↓, interest rates ↑, investment ↓, AD ↓</option>
            <option letter="c">Money supply ↓, interest rates ↓, investment ↑, AD ↑</option>
            <option letter="d">Money supply ↓, interest rates ↓, investment ↓, AD ↓</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When the Fed reduces money supply by selling securities, it raises interest rates in the money market. Higher interest rates discourage borrowing and investment spending, which leads to a decrease in aggregate demand through the monetary policy transmission mechanism.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="8">
        <prompt>A bank has $50,000 in deposits and a 20% reserve requirement. If it currently holds $12,000 in excess reserves, how much more can it lend?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$2,000</option>
            <option letter="b">$10,000</option>
            <option letter="c">$12,000</option>
            <option letter="d">$8,000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Required reserves = 20% × $50,000 = $10,000. The bank has $12,000 in excess reserves (above the required $10,000). Therefore, it can lend out all $12,000 of its excess reserves while still maintaining the required reserve ratio.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="9">
        <prompt>With MPC = 0.75, by how much must taxes change to offset a $200 billion decrease in government spending?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Taxes must decrease by $200 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">Taxes must decrease by $150 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">Taxes must decrease by $250 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">Taxes must decrease by $300 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.75, spending multiplier = 4 and tax multiplier = -3. A $200B spending decrease reduces GDP by $800B (4 × -$200B). To offset this, tax change × -3 must equal +$800B. Therefore, taxes must decrease by $800B ÷ 3 = $150B to restore GDP to its original level.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="10">
        <prompt>What happens in the money market when the Fed conducts open market purchases of government securities?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money supply shifts right, interest rates fall</option>
            <option letter="b">Money supply shifts left, interest rates rise</option>
            <option letter="c">Money demand shifts right, interest rates rise</option>
            <option letter="d">Money demand shifts left, interest rates fall</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>When the Fed buys government securities in open market operations, it increases the money supply by putting more money into circulation. This shifts the money supply curve to the right, leading to lower equilibrium interest rates in the money market while money demand remains constant.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="11">
        <prompt>According to the quantity theory of money, if the Fed increases the money supply by 10% and real GDP grows by 4%, what happens to the price level (assuming constant velocity)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increases by 6%</option>
            <option letter="b">Increases by 14%</option>
            <option letter="c">Increases by 4%</option>
            <option letter="d">Increases by 10%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Using MV = PY, with constant V, if M increases by 10% and Y by 4%, then P must increase by 6% for the equation to balance. This is because the left side increases by 10%, so with Y increasing by 4%, P must increase by the remaining 6% to maintain the equality.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="12">
        <prompt>In the loanable funds market, an increase in expected future profits would:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Shift the supply curve right, lowering interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">Shift the supply curve left, raising interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">Shift the demand curve right, raising interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Shift the demand curve left, lowering interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>When firms expect higher future profits, they want to borrow more money to invest in new projects at any given interest rate. This increases the demand for loanable funds (shifts the demand curve right), resulting in both higher equilibrium interest rates and a larger quantity of funds borrowed.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="13">
        <prompt>What explains the "crowding out" effect of government borrowing?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Government spending directly reduces private consumption</option>
            <option letter="b">Government borrowing raises interest rates, reducing private investment</option>
            <option letter="c">Government taxes reduce disposable income</option>
            <option letter="d">Government regulations restrict private business activity</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Crowding out occurs when increased government borrowing drives up interest rates in the loanable funds market. These higher rates make it more expensive for private businesses to borrow and invest, thus "crowding out" private investment that would have occurred at lower interest rates.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="14">
        <prompt>In the loanable funds market, what happens when new investment opportunities emerge in the economy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Supply curve shifts right, interest rates fall</option>
            <option letter="b">Supply curve shifts left, interest rates rise</option>
            <option letter="c">Demand curve shifts right, interest rates rise</option>
            <option letter="d">Demand curve shifts left, interest rates fall</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>When new investment opportunities emerge, businesses want to borrow more funds at every interest rate to take advantage of these opportunities. This increases the demand for loanable funds (shifts the demand curve right), resulting in higher equilibrium interest rates and a larger quantity of funds borrowed.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="15">
        <prompt>With a required reserve ratio of 10%, what is the maximum amount that can be lent from the 4th deposit in the money creation process, if the initial deposit was $10,000?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$7,290</option>
            <option letter="b">$6,561</option>
            <option letter="c">$9,000</option>
            <option letter="d">$8,100</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Initial deposit: $10,000 → First bank lends $9,000 → Second bank lends $8,100 → Third bank lends $7,290. Each subsequent deposit is 90% of the previous loan (keeping 10% as reserves). The fourth deposit would be $7,290, and the bank could lend 90% of this amount.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="16">
        <prompt>If the money supply is $4 trillion and nominal GDP is $20 trillion, what must happen to M if V falls from 5 to 4 and nominal GDP stays constant?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">M must increase to $3.2 trillion</option>
            <option letter="b">M must increase to $5 trillion</option>
            <option letter="c">M must decrease to $3.2 trillion</option>
            <option letter="d">M must decrease to $5 trillion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Initially, MV = PY means $4T × 5 = $20T. When V falls to 4, to maintain $20T in nominal GDP, M must increase to $5T because $5T × 4 = $20T. This shows how changes in velocity require offsetting changes in money supply to maintain the same nominal GDP.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="17">
        <prompt>In the loanable funds market, what happens when households become more concerned about retirement saving?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Supply shifts left, interest rates rise, quantity decreases</option>
            <option letter="b">Supply shifts right, interest rates fall, quantity increases</option>
            <option letter="c">Demand shifts left, interest rates fall, quantity decreases</option>
            <option letter="d">Demand shifts right, interest rates rise, quantity increases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When households become more concerned about retirement, they increase their saving rate. This increases the supply of loanable funds at every interest rate (shifts the supply curve right), resulting in lower equilibrium interest rates and a larger quantity of funds being loaned in the market.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="18">
        <prompt>What happens to money market equilibrium when the price level decreases?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money demand increases, raising interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">Money demand decreases, lowering interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">Money supply increases, lowering interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">Money supply decreases, raising interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When the price level decreases, people need less money to conduct transactions. This shifts the money demand curve left at every interest rate, resulting in a lower equilibrium interest rate in the money market while the money supply remains constant.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="19">
        <prompt>If velocity is 5 and nominal GDP grows from $20T to $22T, by how much must M increase to keep V constant?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$200 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">$400 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$600 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$800 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Initially, M × 5 = $20T, so M = $4T. To maintain V = 5 with new GDP of $22T, new M × 5 = $22T, so new M = $4.4T. Therefore, M must increase by $4.4T - $4T = $0.4T = $400 billion to keep velocity constant while supporting the higher nominal GDP.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="20">
        <prompt>How does the Marginal Propensity to Save (MPS) affect the size of the fiscal multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A higher MPS creates a larger multiplier</option>
            <option letter="b">A higher MPS creates a smaller multiplier</option>
            <option letter="c">MPS has no effect on the multiplier</option>
            <option letter="d">The relationship depends on the interest rate</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>A higher Marginal Propensity to Save (MPS) creates a smaller fiscal multiplier because more of each additional dollar of income is saved rather than spent. Since MPS = 1 - MPC, and the multiplier is 1/(1-MPC), a higher MPS means less recycling of spending through the economy.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="21">
        <prompt>In the first round of the money creation process with a 20% reserve requirement, if a bank receives a $5000 deposit, what happens in the first three rounds?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">First: lend $4000, Second: lend $3200, Third: lend $2560</option>
            <option letter="b">First: lend $4500, Second: lend $4050, Third: lend $3645</option>
            <option letter="c">First: lend $4000, Second: lend $2000, Third: lend $1000</option>
            <option letter="d">First: lend $3500, Second: lend $2500, Third: lend $1500</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>With 20% reserve requirement: First bank keeps $1000, lends $4000. Second bank keeps $800 (20% of $4000), lends $3200. Third bank keeps $640 (20% of $3200), lends $2560. Each new loan is 80% of the previous deposit, following the reserve requirement pattern.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="22">
        <prompt>With MPC = 0.8, if government spending increases by $100B and monetary policy raises real GDP by an additional $400B, what is the total change in GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$500 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">$900 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$400 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$800 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.8, the fiscal policy multiplier is 5. The $100B spending increase creates $500B in GDP (5 × $100B). The monetary policy directly adds $400B more. Total change = Fiscal effect + Monetary effect = $500B + $400B = $900B, showing how both policies can work together to affect GDP.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="23">
        <prompt>Which describes the main difference between fiscal and monetary policy in affecting aggregate demand?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Fiscal policy works through interest rates, monetary policy through government spending</option>
            <option letter="b">Fiscal policy works through government spending and taxes, monetary policy through interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">Fiscal policy only affects inflation, monetary policy only affects unemployment</option>
            <option letter="d">Fiscal policy only works in the short run, monetary policy only in the long run</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Fiscal policy affects aggregate demand directly through changes in government spending and taxes, while monetary policy works indirectly by changing interest rates, which then affect private spending decisions like consumption and investment.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="24">
        <prompt>If velocity (V) falls by 10% and the Fed wants to maintain the same nominal GDP (PY), what must happen to the money supply (M)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">M must decrease by 10%</option>
            <option letter="b">M must increase by 10%</option>
            <option letter="c">M must increase by 11.11%</option>
            <option letter="d">M must stay constant</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Using MV = PY, if V falls by 10% and we want PY to stay constant, M must increase enough to offset this. When V becomes 0.9 of its original value, M must be multiplied by 1/0.9 (approximately 1.1111) to maintain the same PY, representing an 11.11% increase.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="25">
        <prompt>If the nominal interest rate is 7% and the inflation rate is 3%, what is the real interest rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">10%</option>
            <option letter="b">4%</option>
            <option letter="c">21%</option>
            <option letter="d">2.33%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The real interest rate is calculated by subtracting the inflation rate from the nominal interest rate. In this case, 7% - 3% = 4%. This represents the actual return on investment after accounting for inflation's erosion of purchasing power.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="26">
        <prompt>If a country's MPC is 0.8 and the government cuts taxes by $100 billion while decreasing spending by $80 billion, what is the net effect on GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">No change in GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">$200 billion decrease</option>
            <option letter="c">$400 billion decrease</option>
            <option letter="d">$100 billion decrease</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.8, the spending multiplier is 5 and the tax multiplier is -4. For spending decrease: -$80B × 5 = -$400B. For tax cut: $100B × 4 = +$400B. The net effect is -$400B + $300B = -$100B. The contractionary effect of decreased spending slightly outweighs the expansionary effect of the tax cut.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="27">
        <prompt>If MPC = 0.75 and the government simultaneously increases spending by $200 billion and raises taxes by $160 billion, what is the net effect on GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$200 billion increase</option>
            <option letter="b">$280 billion increase</option>
            <option letter="c">$160 billion increase</option>
            <option letter="d">$120 billion increase</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.75, spending multiplier is 4 and tax multiplier is -3. For spending increase: $200B × 4 = +$800B. For tax increase: $160B × -3 = -$480B. The net effect is +$800B - $480B = +$280B. The expansionary effect of spending outweighs the contractionary effect of taxes.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="28">
        <prompt>If the required reserve ratio is 20% and banks keep 5% excess reserves, what is the actual money multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">5</option>
            <option letter="b">4</option>
            <option letter="c">3.33</option>
            <option letter="d">4.5</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When banks hold excess reserves, the money multiplier is 1/(required ratio + excess ratio). In this case, it's 1/(0.20 + 0.05) = 1/0.25 = 4. The multiplier is smaller than it would be with just required reserves (1/0.20 = 5) because excess reserves reduce lending capacity.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="29">
        <prompt>What happens to the Phillips Curve when there is a positive supply shock?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The curve shifts outward, resulting in higher inflation and higher unemployment</option>
            <option letter="b">The curve shifts inward, resulting in lower inflation and lower unemployment</option>
            <option letter="c">The curve becomes steeper, showing a stronger trade-off between inflation and unemployment</option>
            <option letter="d">The curve becomes flatter, showing a weaker trade-off between inflation and unemployment</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>A positive supply shock (like improved technology or lower input costs) shifts the Phillips Curve inward. This creates a more favorable trade-off, allowing for both lower inflation and lower unemployment simultaneously - a movement toward the origin of the graph.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="30">
        <prompt>With a required reserve ratio of 20%, what is the maximum amount of new money that can be created from a $2000 deposit if banks lend the maximum amount?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$400</option>
            <option letter="b">$1600</option>
            <option letter="c">$8000</option>
            <option letter="d">$10000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>With a 20% reserve requirement, the money multiplier is 1/0.20 = 5. The maximum amount of new money that can be created is the initial deposit times the multiplier: $2000 × 5 = $10000. This assumes banks lend out all excess reserves and borrowers deposit all loans back into the banking system.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="31">
        <prompt>When the economy is in a liquidity trap, why might the Fed turn to quantitative easing?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To raise interest rates above zero</option>
            <option letter="b">To directly affect long-term interest rates when short-term rates are at zero</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce the money supply</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase bank reserve requirements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>In a liquidity trap, when short-term interest rates are at zero, traditional monetary policy becomes ineffective. The Fed may use quantitative easing (buying long-term securities) to directly influence longer-term interest rates and stimulate the economy through other channels.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="32">
        <prompt>When the Federal Reserve conducts open market operations by selling government securities, what sequence occurs in the economy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money supply increases → Interest rates decrease → Investment spending increases → Aggregate Demand increases</option>
            <option letter="b">Money supply decreases → Interest rates increase → Investment spending decreases → Aggregate Demand decreases</option>
            <option letter="c">Money supply increases → Interest rates decrease → Investment spending decreases → Aggregate Demand decreases</option>
            <option letter="d">Money supply decreases → Interest rates increase → Investment spending increases → Aggregate Demand increases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When the Fed sells securities, it takes money out of circulation, reducing the money supply. This makes money more scarce, pushing interest rates up. Higher interest rates discourage borrowing and investment spending, which leads to lower Aggregate Demand.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="33">
        <prompt>How does the balanced budget multiplier explain why a $100 billion increase in both government spending and taxes affects GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It has no effect because spending and taxes offset</option>
            <option letter="b">It increases GDP by $100 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">It decreases GDP by $100 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">It doubles GDP by $200 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The balanced budget multiplier shows that equal increases in government spending and taxes increase GDP by the amount of the spending increase. This occurs because government spending affects all of the initial amount, while the tax increase reduces consumption only by the MPC times the tax amount, resulting in a net positive effect.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="34">
        <prompt>In the long run, according to the quantity theory of money, what is the primary determinant of inflation?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Changes in velocity of money</option>
            <option letter="b">Changes in real GDP</option>
            <option letter="c">Changes in money supply growth</option>
            <option letter="d">Changes in interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The quantity theory of money suggests that in the long run, with velocity (V) and real GDP (Y) relatively stable, the growth rate of the money supply (M) is the primary determinant of inflation (P). This is why sustained inflation is often described as a monetary phenomenon.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="35">
        <prompt>What happens to money demand when real GDP increases?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money demand decreases, leading to lower interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">Money demand increases, leading to higher interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">Money demand stays constant while money supply changes</option>
            <option letter="d">Money demand becomes perfectly elastic</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When real GDP increases, people and businesses need more money for transactions. This increases the demand for money at every interest rate (shifting the money demand curve right), which, with a fixed money supply, results in higher equilibrium interest rates in the money market.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="36">
        <prompt>How does monetary neutrality relate to the equation of exchange (MV = PY)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Changes in M have no effect on either P or Y</option>
            <option letter="b">Changes in M affect only Y in the long run</option>
            <option letter="c">Changes in M affect only P proportionally in the long run</option>
            <option letter="d">Changes in M affect both P and Y equally</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Monetary neutrality states that in the long run, changes in the money supply (M) affect only the price level (P) proportionally, with no long-run effect on real GDP (Y). This occurs because V tends to be stable, so when M changes, P adjusts proportionally while Y returns to its natural level.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="37">
        <prompt>Which Federal Reserve tool has the most immediate and precise effect on the money supply?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Changing the reserve requirement</option>
            <option letter="b">Adjusting the discount rate</option>
            <option letter="c">Conducting open market operations</option>
            <option letter="d">Modifying bank regulations</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Open market operations (buying and selling government securities) are the Fed's most frequently used and precise tool for controlling the money supply. These operations can be conducted quickly, in varying amounts, and can be easily reversed, allowing for fine-tuned adjustments to the money supply.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="38">
        <prompt>Which would most likely shift the money demand curve to the left?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">An increase in real GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">An increase in the price level</option>
            <option letter="c">The introduction of widespread credit card use</option>
            <option letter="d">A decrease in financial technology</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The introduction of widespread credit card use would shift the money demand curve left because people need to hold less money for transactions. When new financial technologies make it easier to make purchases without cash, the demand for money decreases at every interest rate.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="39">
        <prompt>What shifts the supply curve in the loanable funds market to the right?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A decrease in household savings rates</option>
            <option letter="b">An increase in foreign investment in domestic markets</option>
            <option letter="c">A decrease in expected future business opportunities</option>
            <option letter="d">An increase in government borrowing</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The supply of loanable funds increases (shifts right) when foreign investors put more money into domestic markets, when domestic savings rates increase, or when banks become more willing to lend. This increased supply of loanable funds puts downward pressure on real interest rates.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="40">
        <prompt>If real GDP is growing at 3% annually and velocity is constant, what rate of money supply growth would achieve a 2% inflation target?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">1%</option>
            <option letter="b">2%</option>
            <option letter="c">3%</option>
            <option letter="d">5%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>Using MV = PY, with constant V, the growth rate of M must equal the growth rate of P plus the growth rate of Y. To achieve 2% inflation (P) with 3% real GDP growth (Y), money supply must grow by 2% + 3% = 5%. This maintains the equation's equality while hitting the inflation target.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="41">
        <prompt>How does the long-run Phillips Curve differ from the short-run Phillips Curve?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The long-run curve is horizontal while the short-run slopes downward</option>
            <option letter="b">The long-run curve is vertical while the short-run slopes downward</option>
            <option letter="c">The long-run curve slopes upward while the short-run slopes downward</option>
            <option letter="d">Both curves slope downward but at different angles</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The long-run Phillips Curve is vertical at the natural rate of unemployment, showing no permanent trade-off between inflation and unemployment. The short-run curve slopes downward, showing a temporary trade-off as changes in aggregate demand move the economy along the curve.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="42">
        <prompt>If the MPC is 0.8 and there is a tax cut of $500 billion, what is the total change in GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$2000 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">$2500 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$1600 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$2400 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>For a tax cut, the multiplier is -MPC/(1-MPC). With MPC = 0.8, the tax multiplier is -0.8/(1-0.8) = -0.8/0.2 = -4. When taxes decrease by $500 billion, the total change in GDP is $500 billion × 4 = $2000 billion (the negative signs cancel out for a tax cut).</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="43">
        <prompt>If the required reserve ratio is 10% and banks hold 5% excess reserves, how much will $2000 in new deposits add to the money supply?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$20,000</option>
            <option letter="b">$13,333</option>
            <option letter="c">$10,000</option>
            <option letter="d">$15,000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With 10% required reserves plus 5% excess reserves, the total reserve ratio is 15%. The money multiplier is 1/0.15 = 6.67. Therefore, $2000 in new deposits can create a maximum of $2000 × 6.67 = $13,333 in new money, less than if banks held no excess reserves.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="44">
        <prompt>What happens to aggregate demand when the Fed increases the money supply?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">AD shifts right due to lower interest rates and increased spending</option>
            <option letter="b">AD shifts left due to higher interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">AD remains unchanged because money is neutral</option>
            <option letter="d">AD becomes more elastic but doesn't shift</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>When the Fed increases the money supply, interest rates fall, encouraging borrowing and spending. This increased spending on consumption and investment shifts the aggregate demand curve to the right as businesses and consumers respond to the lower cost of borrowing.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="45">
        <prompt>The nominal interest rate is 5% and inflation is 2%. If inflation increases to 4% with no change in the real interest rate, what will be the new nominal interest rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">5%</option>
            <option letter="b">7%</option>
            <option letter="c">3%</option>
            <option letter="d">9%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Initially, real rate = nominal rate - inflation = 5% - 2% = 3%. If inflation increases to 4% and the real rate stays at 3%, the new nominal rate must be: real rate + new inflation = 3% + 4% = 7%. This maintains the same real return while accounting for higher inflation.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="46">
        <prompt>If MPC = 0.8 and the government increases spending by $100 billion while raising taxes by $150 billion, what is the net change in GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$100 billion decrease</option>
            <option letter="b">$200 billion decrease</option>
            <option letter="c">$300 billion decrease</option>
            <option letter="d">$400 billion decrease</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.8, the spending multiplier is 5 and the tax multiplier is -4. The net effect is: ($100B × 5) + ($150B × -4) = $500B - $600B = -$100B. This shows how combining expansionary spending with larger contractionary taxation leads to a net decrease in GDP.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="47">
        <prompt>Which best describes the relationship between the discount rate and the federal funds rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The discount rate is typically lower than the federal funds rate</option>
            <option letter="b">The discount rate is typically higher than the federal funds rate</option>
            <option letter="c">The discount rate and federal funds rate are always equal</option>
            <option letter="d">The discount rate and federal funds rate move in opposite directions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The discount rate (rate at which banks borrow from the Fed) is typically kept higher than the federal funds rate (rate at which banks borrow from each other) to encourage banks to borrow from each other first before turning to the Fed as a lender of last resort.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="48">
        <prompt>During which phase of the business cycle would expansionary fiscal policy be most appropriate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">When there is an inflationary gap</option>
            <option letter="b">When there is a recessionary gap</option>
            <option letter="c">When the economy is at full employment</option>
            <option letter="d">When there is stagflation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Expansionary fiscal policy (increased government spending or tax cuts) is most appropriate during a recessionary gap when actual GDP is below potential GDP. This policy helps stimulate aggregate demand to close the gap and bring the economy back to full employment.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="49">
        <prompt>A Treasury bill has a shorter maturity than a Treasury note because:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Treasury bills mature in less than one year</option>
            <option letter="b">Treasury bills mature in 1-5 years</option>
            <option letter="c">Treasury bills mature in 5-10 years</option>
            <option letter="d">Treasury bills mature in over 10 years</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Treasury bills (T-bills) are short-term government securities that mature in less than one year, while Treasury notes mature in 1-5 years, and Treasury bonds mature in periods longer than 5 years. This maturity difference affects their interest rates and price sensitivity.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="50">
        <prompt>Which describes a recessionary gap in terms of Potential GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Actual GDP equals Potential GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">Actual GDP exceeds Potential GDP</option>
            <option letter="c">Actual GDP is less than Potential GDP</option>
            <option letter="d">Potential GDP is growing faster than Actual GDP</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>A recessionary gap occurs when actual GDP falls below potential GDP, indicating the economy is operating below its full employment level. This gap represents unused productive capacity and higher-than-natural unemployment, suggesting the economy is performing below its capabilities.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="51">
        <prompt>If the MPC (Marginal Propensity to Consume) is 0.75, what is the MPS (Marginal Propensity to Save)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">0.75</option>
            <option letter="b">1.75</option>
            <option letter="c">0.25</option>
            <option letter="d">1.25</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The Marginal Propensity to Save (MPS) equals 1 minus the Marginal Propensity to Consume (MPC). Since MPC = 0.75, MPS = 1 - 0.75 = 0.25. This means for each additional dollar of income, 75 cents is consumed and 25 cents is saved.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="52">
        <prompt>How does an increase in the reserve requirement affect the money supply?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increases the money supply by increasing bank lending</option>
            <option letter="b">Decreases the money supply by reducing bank lending</option>
            <option letter="c">Has no effect on the money supply</option>
            <option letter="d">Only affects the money supply during recessions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When the Fed increases the reserve requirement, banks must hold more reserves against deposits, leaving less money available for lending. This reduces the money multiplier and decreases the money supply as banks can create less money through the lending process.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="53">
        <prompt>What happens to the money demand curve when GDP decreases significantly?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Shifts right because people need more money for transactions</option>
            <option letter="b">Shifts left because people need less money for transactions</option>
            <option letter="c">Becomes steeper but doesn't shift</option>
            <option letter="d">Becomes more elastic but doesn't shift</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When GDP decreases, fewer transactions occur in the economy, so people need less money to conduct their reduced level of business. This shifts the money demand curve to the left at every interest rate, as less money is demanded for the lower level of economic activity.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="54">
        <prompt>If velocity (V) is constant at 5, the money supply (M) grows by 8%, and real GDP (Y) grows by 3%, what happens to the price level (P)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">P increases by 3%</option>
            <option letter="b">P increases by 5%</option>
            <option letter="c">P increases by 8%</option>
            <option letter="d">P increases by 11%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Using MV = PY with constant V, if M increases by 8% and Y by 3%, then P must increase by 5% for the equation to balance. This is because the left side increases by 8%, so with Y increasing by 3%, P must increase by the remaining 5% to maintain the equality.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="55">
        <prompt>If nominal GDP is $24 trillion and velocity is 6, what happens to the money supply (M) if velocity drops to 4 and nominal GDP falls to $20 trillion?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">M increases from $4T to $5T</option>
            <option letter="b">M decreases from $4T to $3T</option>
            <option letter="c">M remains constant at $4T</option>
            <option letter="d">M increases from $4T to $6T</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Initial M = $24T/6 = $4T. After changes, new M = $20T/4 = $5T. Despite nominal GDP falling, the larger proportional drop in velocity (from 6 to 4) means more money is needed to support the new level of transactions. M increases by $1T to maintain the equation of exchange.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="56">
        <prompt>What causes movement along the short-run Phillips Curve rather than a shift?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Changes in expected inflation</option>
            <option letter="b">Supply shocks</option>
            <option letter="c">Changes in aggregate demand due to monetary or fiscal policy</option>
            <option letter="d">Changes in the natural rate of unemployment</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Movements along the short-run Phillips Curve occur when changes in aggregate demand (from monetary or fiscal policy) cause unemployment and inflation to move in opposite directions. Supply shocks and changes in expectations would shift the entire curve rather than cause movement along it.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="57">
        <prompt>If the nominal interest rate is 8% and inflation is expected to be 3%, what is the real interest rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">11%</option>
            <option letter="b">5%</option>
            <option letter="c">2.67%</option>
            <option letter="d">-5%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The real interest rate equals the nominal interest rate minus the expected inflation rate. In this case, 8% - 3% = 5%. This represents the actual return on investment after accounting for the erosion of purchasing power due to inflation.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="58">
        <prompt>A bank has a 15% required reserve ratio and $300,000 in deposits. If it's currently holding $60,000 in reserves, how much in excess reserves does it have?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$15,000</option>
            <option letter="b">$45,000</option>
            <option letter="c">$30,000</option>
            <option letter="d">$60,000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Required reserves = 15% × $300,000 = $45,000. The bank is holding $60,000 in actual reserves. Excess reserves = Actual reserves - Required reserves = $60,000 - $45,000 = $15,000. This is the amount the bank could lend out while still meeting its reserve requirement.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="59">
        <prompt>How does an increase in the natural rate of unemployment affect the Phillips Curve?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Shifts both short-run and long-run curves right</option>
            <option letter="b">Only shifts the long-run curve right</option>
            <option letter="c">Only affects the slope of the curves</option>
            <option letter="d">Has no effect on either curve</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>When the natural rate of unemployment increases, both the long-run Phillips Curve (which is vertical at the natural rate) and the short-run Phillips Curve shift to the right. This shows that all inflation rates are now associated with higher unemployment levels.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="60">
        <prompt>Why is velocity (V) in the equation of exchange (MV = PY) considered "sticky" in the short run?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It changes quickly with interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">It's directly controlled by the Fed</option>
            <option letter="c">It depends on relatively stable payment habits and financial technology</option>
            <option letter="d">It varies with the money supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Velocity is considered "sticky" because it depends on established payment habits, financial institutions, and technology, which change slowly over time. People's patterns of holding and spending money tend to be stable in the short run, making V relatively constant.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="61">
        <prompt>In the short-run Phillips Curve, what causes movement along the curve rather than a shift of the curve?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Changes in expected inflation</option>
            <option letter="b">Changes in aggregate supply</option>
            <option letter="c">Changes in aggregate demand</option>
            <option letter="d">Changes in productivity</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Movement along the short-run Phillips Curve occurs when changes in aggregate demand cause unemployment and inflation to move in opposite directions. Changes in expected inflation or aggregate supply would shift the entire curve, while changes in AD create the trade-off represented by the curve.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="62">
        <prompt>With MPC = 0.8, suppose Congress increases government spending by $50 billion but also raises taxes by $40 billion. What is the net effect on GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$90 billion increase</option>
            <option letter="b">$50 billion increase</option>
            <option letter="c">$40 billion increase</option>
            <option letter="d">$60 billion increase</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.8, spending multiplier = 5 and tax multiplier = -4. Spending effect: $50B × 5 = +$250B. Tax effect: $40B × -4 = -$160B. Net effect = +$250B - $160B = +$90B increase in GDP. The expansionary effect of spending outweighs the contractionary effect of taxes.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="63">
        <prompt>If the reserve requirement is 10% and banks hold no excess reserves, what is the money multiplier, and how much new money can be created from $1000 in new deposits?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Multiplier = 10, New money = $10,000</option>
            <option letter="b">Multiplier = 5, New money = $5,000</option>
            <option letter="c">Multiplier = 0.1, New money = $100</option>
            <option letter="d">Multiplier = 1, New money = $1,000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The money multiplier equals 1/reserve requirement ratio. With a 10% (0.1) requirement, the multiplier is 1/0.1 = 10. Therefore, $1000 in new deposits can create up to $1000 × 10 = $10,000 in new money through the banking system's lending process.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="64">
        <prompt>What happens to the Phillips Curve when there is a favorable supply shock?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The curve shifts outward showing higher inflation at all unemployment rates</option>
            <option letter="b">The curve shifts inward showing lower inflation at all unemployment rates</option>
            <option letter="c">The curve becomes steeper showing a stronger trade-off</option>
            <option letter="d">The curve becomes more vertical showing no trade-off</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>A favorable supply shock (like lower oil prices or improved technology) shifts the Phillips Curve inward. This means the economy can achieve lower inflation rates at any given unemployment rate, representing an improved trade-off between inflation and unemployment.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="65">
        <prompt>In the money market, what happens when new financial technology reduces the amount of money people need to hold?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money demand shifts right, interest rates rise</option>
            <option letter="b">Money demand shifts left, interest rates fall</option>
            <option letter="c">Money supply shifts right, interest rates fall</option>
            <option letter="d">Money supply shifts left, interest rates rise</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When financial technology (like digital payments) makes it easier to conduct transactions with less cash, people need to hold less money at every interest rate. This shifts the money demand curve left, resulting in lower equilibrium interest rates while the money supply remains constant.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="66">
        <prompt>If the nominal interest rate is 7% and expected inflation rises from 3% to 5%, what happens to the real interest rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Increases from 4% to 6%</option>
            <option letter="b">Decreases from 4% to 2%</option>
            <option letter="c">Remains constant at 4%</option>
            <option letter="d">Increases from 2% to 4%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The real interest rate equals the nominal rate minus expected inflation. Initially, real rate = 7% - 3% = 4%. After inflation expectations rise, new real rate = 7% - 5% = 2%. With a constant nominal rate, higher expected inflation reduces the real interest rate by the same amount.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="67">
        <prompt>In the loanable funds market, what happens when foreigners increase their investment in domestic markets?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Supply shifts right, interest rates fall, quantity increases</option>
            <option letter="b">Supply shifts left, interest rates rise, quantity decreases</option>
            <option letter="c">Demand shifts right, interest rates rise, quantity increases</option>
            <option letter="d">Demand shifts left, interest rates fall, quantity decreases</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>When foreigners invest more in domestic markets, they increase the supply of loanable funds available at each interest rate (shifting the supply curve right). This greater supply leads to lower equilibrium interest rates and a larger quantity of funds being loaned in the market.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="68">
        <prompt>If MPC = 0.75 and government spending increases by $200 billion, what is the total change in GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$200 billion</option>
            <option letter="b">$400 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$600 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$800 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.75, the spending multiplier is 1/(1-0.75) = 1/0.25 = 4. When government spending increases by $200 billion, the total change in GDP is $200 billion × 4 = $800 billion, as the initial spending creates multiple rounds of additional spending.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="69">
        <prompt>How does an increase in expected inflation affect the nominal interest rate in the loanable funds market?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It has no effect on nominal interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">It decreases nominal interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">It increases nominal interest rates by the same amount</option>
            <option letter="d">It makes nominal interest rates more volatile</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>When expected inflation increases, lenders demand higher nominal interest rates to maintain their real return. The nominal rate increases by approximately the same amount as the increase in expected inflation, following the Fisher equation where nominal rate equals real rate plus expected inflation.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="70">
        <prompt>Why might fiscal policy have a shorter time lag than monetary policy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Fiscal policy takes longer to implement</option>
            <option letter="b">Direct government spending affects AD more immediately than interest rate changes</option>
            <option letter="c">Fiscal policy requires more political consensus</option>
            <option letter="d">Monetary policy works faster through financial markets</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When implemented, fiscal policy through direct government spending has a more immediate effect on aggregate demand compared to monetary policy, which must work through the interest rate channel and affect private spending decisions, a process that takes more time to impact the real economy.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="71">
        <prompt>If the federal funds rate is below the discount rate, banks will typically:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Borrow from the Federal Reserve</option>
            <option letter="b">Borrow from other banks</option>
            <option letter="c">Stop lending completely</option>
            <option letter="d">Increase their reserve requirements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When the federal funds rate (the rate banks charge each other) is lower than the discount rate (the rate the Fed charges), banks will prefer to borrow from other banks rather than from the Fed. This is why the discount rate is typically kept higher than the federal funds rate.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="72">
        <prompt>Which Treasury security would likely offer the highest interest rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">3-month Treasury bill</option>
            <option letter="b">2-year Treasury note</option>
            <option letter="c">5-year Treasury note</option>
            <option letter="d">30-year Treasury bond</option>
        </options>
        <answer>d</answer>
        <explanation>The 30-year Treasury bond typically offers the highest interest rate because it has the longest maturity. This higher rate compensates investors for tying up their money for a longer period and taking on greater interest rate risk and inflation risk over the extended time horizon.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="73">
        <prompt>If the economy is experiencing both high unemployment and high inflation, this scenario is known as:</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Deflation</option>
            <option letter="b">Hyperinflation</option>
            <option letter="c">Stagflation</option>
            <option letter="d">Reflation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Stagflation occurs when the economy experiences both high unemployment (stagnation) and high inflation simultaneously. This challenges the traditional Phillips Curve relationship and often results from negative supply shocks, such as rising oil prices, that both reduce output and increase prices.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="74">
        <prompt>How does an inflationary gap affect the price level over time?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The price level gradually falls until the gap closes</option>
            <option letter="b">The price level remains constant despite the gap</option>
            <option letter="c">The price level gradually rises until the gap closes</option>
            <option letter="d">The price level falls then rises cyclically</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>In an inflationary gap, where actual GDP exceeds potential GDP, upward pressure on wages and prices occurs. The price level gradually rises over time as this excess demand pushes up costs, eventually bringing actual GDP back to potential GDP level.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="75">
        <prompt>What happens in the loanable funds market when businesses become more optimistic about future sales?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The supply curve shifts right, lowering interest rates</option>
            <option letter="b">The supply curve shifts left, raising interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">The demand curve shifts right, raising interest rates</option>
            <option letter="d">The demand curve shifts left, lowering interest rates</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>When businesses become more optimistic about future sales, they want to borrow more to invest in expansion at every interest rate. This increases the demand for loanable funds (shifts the demand curve right), which results in higher equilibrium interest rates and a larger quantity of funds loaned.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="76">
        <prompt>What happens to the demand for money when the price level in the economy increases?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Money demand decreases due to inflation expectations</option>
            <option letter="b">Money demand increases as more money is needed for transactions</option>
            <option letter="c">Money demand stays constant regardless of price level</option>
            <option letter="d">Money demand becomes perfectly elastic</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When the price level increases, people need to hold more money to conduct the same amount of real transactions. This causes the money demand curve to shift to the right, as more money is demanded at every interest rate to maintain the same purchasing power.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="77">
        <prompt>What typically happens to velocity (V) in the equation of exchange (MV = PY) during a recession?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Velocity increases as people spend more quickly</option>
            <option letter="b">Velocity decreases as people hold onto money longer</option>
            <option letter="c">Velocity remains exactly constant</option>
            <option letter="d">Velocity increases proportionally with money supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>During recessions, velocity typically decreases because people and businesses become more cautious with spending and prefer to hold onto money longer. This precautionary behavior means each dollar circulates more slowly through the economy, reducing the velocity of money.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="78">
        <prompt>If velocity = 6 and nominal GDP = $24 trillion, what money supply (M) is needed? If velocity then falls to 4, how much must M increase to maintain the same GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Initial M = $4T, New M = $6T</option>
            <option letter="b">Initial M = $6T, New M = $8T</option>
            <option letter="c">Initial M = $4T, New M = $8T</option>
            <option letter="d">Initial M = $6T, New M = $4T</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Using MV = PY: Initial M = $24T/6 = $4T. When V falls to 4, new M = $24T/4 = $6T. The money supply must increase by $2T to offset the decrease in velocity and maintain the same level of nominal GDP.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="79">
        <prompt>If the economy has an MPC of 0.8 and the government increases both spending and taxes by $300 billion, what is the net change in GDP?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$0 billion (they cancel out)</option>
            <option letter="b">$300 billion</option>
            <option letter="c">$600 billion</option>
            <option letter="d">$1200 billion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>This is the balanced budget multiplier. When G and T both increase by the same amount, the net multiplier is 1, regardless of the MPC. The spending increase multiplier (5) times $300B minus the tax increase multiplier (-4) times $300B equals a net change of $300B in GDP.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="80">
        <prompt>With a required reserve ratio of 10%, how much can banks lend from a new deposit of $5000?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$500</option>
            <option letter="b">$4500</option>
            <option letter="c">$5000</option>
            <option letter="d">$50000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With a 10% reserve requirement, banks must keep $500 (10% of $5000) as required reserves. They can lend out the remaining 90%, which is $4500. This initial lending begins the money creation process through the banking system's money multiplier effect.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="81">
        <prompt>In a simple deposit expansion, if the required reserve ratio is 25% and a bank receives a new deposit of $10,000, what is the maximum amount this single bank can lend?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$2,500</option>
            <option letter="b">$7,500</option>
            <option letter="c">$30,000</option>
            <option letter="d">$40,000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With a 25% reserve requirement, the bank must keep $2,500 (25% of $10,000) as required reserves. The bank can lend out the remaining 75%, which is $7,500. This is different from the total money creation possible through the entire banking system, which would be determined by the money multiplier.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="82">
        <prompt>If the Marginal Propensity to Consume (MPC) is 0.8, what is the size of the spending multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">0.8</option>
            <option letter="b">1.25</option>
            <option letter="c">5.0</option>
            <option letter="d">0.2</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The spending multiplier is calculated as 1/(1-MPC). With MPC = 0.8, the multiplier is 1/(1-0.8) = 1/0.2 = 5.0. This means each dollar of government spending or other autonomous expenditure changes total spending by $5.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="83">
        <prompt>In a fractional reserve system with a 10% required reserve ratio, what sequence of deposits and loans occurs when someone deposits $1000?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$1000 → $900 → $810 → $729 → continuing</option>
            <option letter="b">$1000 → $100 → $90 → $81 → continuing</option>
            <option letter="c">$1000 → $800 → $640 → $512 → continuing</option>
            <option letter="d">$1000 → $500 → $250 → $125 → continuing</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>With 10% reserves: First bank keeps $100, lends $900. Second bank keeps $90 (10% of $900), lends $810. Third bank keeps $81, lends $729. Each new deposit is 90% of the previous loan, creating a decreasing sequence that ultimately creates a total money supply increase of $10,000.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="84">
        <prompt>Which best describes how the Marginal Propensity to Consume (MPC) affects the size of the spending multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">A larger MPC leads to a smaller multiplier</option>
            <option letter="b">A larger MPC leads to a larger multiplier</option>
            <option letter="c">The MPC has no effect on the multiplier</option>
            <option letter="d">The multiplier depends only on government spending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>A larger MPC creates a larger multiplier because when people spend more of each additional dollar (higher MPC), it creates more rounds of spending. The multiplier formula is 1/(1-MPC), so as MPC increases, the denominator gets smaller, making the multiplier larger.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="85">
        <prompt>What primarily determines the difference in interest rates between Treasury bills and Treasury bonds?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The Federal Reserve's monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="b">The government's credit rating</option>
            <option letter="c">The length of time until maturity</option>
            <option letter="d">The current inflation rate</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The main difference in interest rates between Treasury bills and bonds is their maturity length. Bonds have longer maturities (over 5 years) than bills (less than 1 year), so they typically pay higher interest rates to compensate investors for the longer time commitment and greater interest rate risk.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="86">
        <prompt>Which is an example of an automatic stabilizer during a recession?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Congress passing a new stimulus package</option>
            <option letter="b">The Fed lowering interest rates</option>
            <option letter="c">Progressive income tax collecting less revenue</option>
            <option letter="d">The President proposing new spending programs</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Progressive income tax acts as an automatic stabilizer because during a recession, as incomes fall, people automatically pay less in taxes due to the progressive tax structure. This happens without requiring any new legislation, helping to maintain disposable income and consumer spending.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="87">
        <prompt>How do required reserves affect the money multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Higher required reserves increase the money multiplier</option>
            <option letter="b">Higher required reserves decrease the money multiplier</option>
            <option letter="c">Required reserves have no effect on the money multiplier</option>
            <option letter="d">Required reserves only affect the money multiplier during recessions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Higher required reserve ratios decrease the money multiplier because banks must hold more reserves for each dollar deposited, leaving less money available for lending. The money multiplier is calculated as 1/required reserve ratio, so a higher ratio leads to a smaller multiplier.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="88">
        <prompt>In the long run Phillips Curve, what happens to the unemployment rate when inflation changes?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Unemployment increases with higher inflation</option>
            <option letter="b">Unemployment decreases with higher inflation</option>
            <option letter="c">Unemployment stays at the natural rate regardless of inflation</option>
            <option letter="d">Unemployment and inflation move in opposite directions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The long-run Phillips Curve is vertical at the natural rate of unemployment, indicating that there is no permanent trade-off between inflation and unemployment. In the long run, the unemployment rate returns to its natural rate regardless of the inflation rate as expectations adjust.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="89">
        <prompt>In the money market, why is the money supply curve typically drawn as a vertical line?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Because money supply responds to changes in GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">Because money supply is determined by the Fed, regardless of interest rate</option>
            <option letter="c">Because money supply changes with inflation</option>
            <option letter="d">Because money supply depends on bank lending</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>The money supply curve is vertical because it is fixed by Federal Reserve policy at any given time and does not automatically respond to changes in the interest rate. The Fed determines the money supply through its monetary policy tools, making it independent of the market interest rate.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="90">
        <prompt>What is the primary goal of the Federal Reserve's monetary policy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To maximize employment only</option>
            <option letter="b">To control inflation only</option>
            <option letter="c">To balance employment, price stability, and economic growth</option>
            <option letter="d">To minimize government debt</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>The Federal Reserve has a dual mandate to promote maximum employment and price stability, while supporting moderate long-term interest rates. This means balancing multiple objectives: maintaining high employment, controlling inflation, and fostering sustainable economic growth.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="91">
        <prompt>How does TANF (Temporary Aid to Needy Families) function as an automatic stabilizer?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It automatically increases taxes during economic booms</option>
            <option letter="b">It automatically provides more benefits when unemployment rises</option>
            <option letter="c">It automatically adjusts interest rates with inflation</option>
            <option letter="d">It automatically increases government spending on infrastructure</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>TANF works as an automatic stabilizer because during economic downturns, more families become eligible for benefits without requiring new legislation. This automatic increase in government transfers helps maintain consumption levels and stabilize aggregate demand when the economy weakens.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="92">
        <prompt>Which of the following best demonstrates the concept of crowding out in fiscal policy?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Government spending increases total GDP</option>
            <option letter="b">Government borrowing raises interest rates, reducing private investment</option>
            <option letter="c">Tax increases reduce consumer spending</option>
            <option letter="d">Inflation reduces purchasing power</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Crowding out occurs when increased government borrowing drives up interest rates in the loanable funds market. These higher rates make it more expensive for private businesses to borrow and invest, thus "crowding out" private investment that would have otherwise occurred.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="93">
        <prompt>If banks hold excess reserves, what happens to the effectiveness of the money multiplier?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The money multiplier becomes larger</option>
            <option letter="b">The money multiplier becomes smaller</option>
            <option letter="c">The money multiplier stays the same</option>
            <option letter="d">The money multiplier becomes negative</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When banks hold excess reserves (more than required), the money multiplier becomes smaller because less money is being loaned out and re-deposited. Since the multiplication process depends on banks lending out their excess reserves, holding excess reserves reduces the money multiplier's effectiveness.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="94">
        <prompt>If MPC = 0.8 and MPS = 0.2, what happens to consumption and saving when income increases by $5000?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Consumption +$4000, Saving +$1000</option>
            <option letter="b">Consumption +$1000, Saving +$4000</option>
            <option letter="c">Consumption +$2500, Saving +$2500</option>
            <option letter="d">Consumption +$3000, Saving +$2000</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.8, $4000 of the $5000 increase goes to consumption (0.8 × $5000). With MPS = 0.2, $1000 goes to saving (0.2 × $5000). This shows how MPC + MPS = 1, as each additional dollar must be either consumed or saved.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="95">
        <prompt>In a liquidity trap scenario, why might traditional monetary policy become ineffective?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Interest rates are already at their maximum level</option>
            <option letter="b">Interest rates are already at or near zero, so they cannot be lowered further</option>
            <option letter="c">Banks have too much liquidity</option>
            <option letter="d">The money supply is too low</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>In a liquidity trap, interest rates are already at or very near zero (the "zero lower bound"). Since the Fed cannot push rates significantly below zero, traditional monetary policy of lowering rates to stimulate borrowing and investment becomes ineffective.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="96">
        <prompt>What happens to velocity in MV = PY when new financial technology makes transactions more efficient?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Velocity decreases because less money is needed</option>
            <option letter="b">Velocity increases because each dollar is used more frequently</option>
            <option letter="c">Velocity stays constant regardless of technology</option>
            <option letter="d">Velocity becomes more volatile</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>When financial technology improves transaction efficiency, each dollar can be used more frequently for transactions. This increases velocity (V) because the same amount of money can support more transactions, meaning each dollar circulates through the economy more quickly.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="97">
        <prompt>If nominal interest rates are 6% and real interest rates are 2%, what is the expected inflation rate?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">8%</option>
            <option letter="b">4%</option>
            <option letter="c">3%</option>
            <option letter="d">12%</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Using the Fisher equation, nominal interest rate = real interest rate + expected inflation rate. Therefore, expected inflation = nominal rate - real rate = 6% - 2% = 4%. This represents what people expect inflation to be based on the difference between nominal and real interest rates.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="98">
        <prompt>If MPC = 0.75 and income increases by $1000, what is the change in saving?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$750</option>
            <option letter="b">$250</option>
            <option letter="c">$1000</option>
            <option letter="d">$0</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>With MPC = 0.75, the Marginal Propensity to Save (MPS) = 1 - MPC = 0.25. When income increases by $1000, consumption increases by $750 (MPC × $1000) and saving increases by $250 (MPS × $1000), as each additional dollar must be either consumed or saved.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="99">
        <prompt>If velocity (V) is 4, nominal GDP (PY) is $20 trillion, what is the money supply (M)?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">$80 trillion</option>
            <option letter="b">$5 trillion</option>
            <option letter="c">$16 trillion</option>
            <option letter="d">$24 trillion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>b</answer>
        <explanation>Using the equation of exchange MV = PY, we can solve for M: M = PY/V. With PY = $20 trillion and V = 4, M = $20 trillion/4 = $5 trillion. This represents the money supply needed to support this level of nominal GDP at this velocity.</explanation>
    </question>
<question number="100">
        <prompt>If velocity is initially 5 and money supply grows 10% while real GDP grows 4%, what happens to velocity if prices rise by 4%?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">Velocity increases to 5.2</option>
            <option letter="b">Velocity decreases to 4.8</option>
            <option letter="c">Velocity remains at 5</option>
            <option letter="d">Velocity decreases to 4.9</option>
        </options>
        <answer>c</answer>
        <explanation>Using MV = PY: The left side grows by 10% (M). The right side grows by 8% (4% P + 4% Y). Since 10% ≠ 8%, V must adjust. The ratio of right to left growth is 1.08/1.10 = 0.982. Therefore, V changes by this factor: 5 × 0.982 = 4.91, then rounds to 5. Velocity remains essentially constant.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>