<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="1">
        <prompt>What was the immediate cause of the 1893 economic depression?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">The failure of the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad</option>
            <option letter="b">The passage of the Sherman Silver Purchase Act</option>
            <option letter="c">A decline in agricultural exports</option>
            <option letter="d">The collapse of the stock market</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Panic of 1893 was triggered by the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad declaring bankruptcy, leading to a domino effect of bank failures and business closures.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="2">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Pullman Strike of 1894?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It marked the first use of federal troops to break a strike</option>
            <option letter="b">It led to the creation of Labor Day as a federal holiday</option>
            <option letter="c">It resulted in the formation of the AFL</option>
            <option letter="d">It ended in a victory for the workers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>President Cleveland's use of federal troops to break the Pullman Strike set a precedent for federal intervention in labor disputes and demonstrated the government's alignment with business interests.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="3">
        <prompt>What was the main argument in Booker T. Washington's Atlanta Compromise speech?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">African Americans should focus on economic self-reliance before political rights</option>
            <option letter="b">Immediate political equality was necessary for racial progress</option>
            <option letter="c">The federal government should enforce civil rights laws</option>
            <option letter="d">Social integration should be the primary goal</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Washington advocated for African Americans to focus on economic self-improvement and industrial education rather than immediate social and political equality, a position that became known as the Atlanta Compromise.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="4">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the USS Maine explosion in 1898?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It provided the immediate justification for war with Spain</option>
            <option letter="b">It demonstrated the need for naval reform</option>
            <option letter="c">It led to improved ship construction methods</option>
            <option letter="d">It caused a diplomatic crisis with Britain</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The explosion of the USS Maine in Havana harbor, though never conclusively linked to Spain, provided the immediate catalyst for the Spanish-American War after yellow journalism inflamed public opinion.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
