<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="49">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Atlanta Exposition of 1895?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To showcase the New South's industrial progress</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote civil rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To celebrate Confederate history</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose industrialization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Atlanta Exposition was designed to showcase the South's industrial development and attract Northern investment, providing the setting for Booker T. Washington's famous compromise speech.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="50">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Jane Addams's Hull House?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It pioneered settlement house work in American cities</option>
            <option letter="b">It provided only housing assistance</option>
            <option letter="c">It focused on rural poverty</option>
            <option letter="d">It served only immigrant women</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Hull House pioneered the settlement house movement in America, providing educational, cultural, and social services to urban immigrants while promoting social reform.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="51">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of literacy tests on voting rights?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They disenfranchised African Americans through discriminatory application</option>
            <option letter="b">They improved education levels</option>
            <option letter="c">They increased voter turnout</option>
            <option letter="d">They applied equally to all races</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Literacy tests were applied discriminatorily to prevent African Americans from voting while allowing illiterate whites to vote through grandfather clauses and other exemptions.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="52">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Philippine-American War?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To establish American colonial control over the Philippines</option>
            <option letter="b">To grant immediate independence</option>
            <option letter="c">To protect Filipino rights</option>
            <option letter="d">To prevent Japanese expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The U.S. fought to establish colonial control over the Philippines against Filipino independence fighters, resulting in a brutal guerrilla war and eventual American victory.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
