<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="61">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the Rough Riders' charge up San Juan Hill?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It became a symbol of American heroism in the Spanish-American War</option>
            <option letter="b">It ended the war immediately</option>
            <option letter="c">It led to Spanish victory</option>
            <option letter="d">It prevented Cuban independence</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Rough Riders' charge, though actually up Kettle Hill, became a celebrated symbol of American heroism and helped launch Theodore Roosevelt's political career.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="62">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Cleveland-Morgan deal during the 1895 financial crisis?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To maintain the gold standard by selling bonds to a banking syndicate</option>
            <option letter="b">To adopt free silver</option>
            <option letter="c">To nationalize banks</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase inflation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>President Cleveland worked with J.P. Morgan to maintain the gold standard by selling government bonds to a banking syndicate, preventing a financial collapse.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="63">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the People's Party (Populists) in the 1892 election?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To represent farmers' and workers' interests against industrial capitalism</option>
            <option letter="b">To support big business</option>
            <option letter="c">To maintain the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote industrial growth</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Populists sought to represent farmers and workers against industrial capitalism, advocating for monetary reform, government ownership of railroads, and other reforms.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="64">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Battle of Manila Bay?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established American naval superiority in the Pacific</option>
            <option letter="b">It secured Philippine independence</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected Spanish interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It prevented colonial expansion</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Commodore Dewey's victory at Manila Bay destroyed the Spanish fleet, established American naval superiority in the Pacific, and led to U.S. acquisition of the Philippines.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
