<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="77">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of Frederick Jackson Turner's Frontier Thesis?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To explain American democracy through frontier expansion</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose westward expansion</option>
            <option letter="c">To protect Native Americans</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote urbanization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Turner argued that the American frontier experience shaped American democracy and character, presenting his influential thesis at the 1893 Columbian Exposition.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="78">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Farmers' Alliances?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">They organized farmers and led to the Populist movement</option>
            <option letter="b">They supported big business</option>
            <option letter="c">They opposed political action</option>
            <option letter="d">They promoted industrialization</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Farmers' Alliances organized farmers for economic cooperation and education, laying the groundwork for the Populist movement of the 1890s.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="79">
        <prompt>What was the main impact of Edward Bellamy's Looking Backward?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It popularized nationalist clubs and socialist ideas</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported laissez-faire capitalism</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted conservative values</option>
            <option letter="d">It criticized reform movements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Bellamy's utopian novel popularized socialist ideas and led to the formation of nationalist clubs dedicated to achieving his vision of a cooperative society.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="80">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Naval Act of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To build a modern American naval fleet</option>
            <option letter="b">To reduce military spending</option>
            <option letter="c">To maintain isolation</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect coastal waters only</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Naval Act of 1890 authorized the construction of modern battleships, beginning the transformation of the U.S. Navy into a world-class naval power.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
