<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="89">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the American Federation of Labor's "pure and simple" unionism?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To focus exclusively on workplace improvements for skilled workers</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote socialist revolution</option>
            <option letter="c">To organize all workers</option>
            <option letter="d">To support political parties</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The AFL under Gompers pursued "pure and simple" unionism, focusing on immediate workplace improvements for skilled workers rather than broader social or political reform.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="90">
        <prompt>What was the significance of Liliuokalani's proposed constitution?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It prompted American planters to overthrow the Hawaiian monarchy</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened Hawaiian independence</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected American interests</option>
            <option letter="d">It promoted democracy</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Queen Liliuokalani's attempt to strengthen native Hawaiian power through a new constitution prompted American planters to overthrow her with U.S. military support.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="91">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the national banking system in the 1890s?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It created an inelastic currency that worsened economic problems</option>
            <option letter="b">It provided stable monetary policy</option>
            <option letter="c">It prevented bank failures</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased money supply</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The national banking system created an inelastic currency that couldn't expand to meet seasonal demands, contributing to financial instability and economic problems.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="92">
        <prompt>What was the primary goal of the Social Gospel movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To apply Christian principles to social problems</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote individual salvation</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose immigration</option>
            <option letter="d">To support laissez-faire economics</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Social Gospel movement sought to apply Christian principles to address social problems like poverty, inequality, and urban conditions, promoting social reform through religious activism.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
