<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="133">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of Alice Fletcher's work with Native Americans?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">She implemented the Dawes Act's land allotment program</option>
            <option letter="b">She protected tribal lands</option>
            <option letter="c">She preserved native culture</option>
            <option letter="d">She opposed assimilation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>As a special agent, Fletcher implemented the Dawes Act's land allotment program, believing that private property would help Native Americans assimilate into white society.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="134">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the People's Party Convention of 1892?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established the first national third-party platform</option>
            <option letter="b">It supported the gold standard</option>
            <option letter="c">It opposed labor reform</option>
            <option letter="d">It united with Democrats</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The 1892 People's Party Convention created the first comprehensive third-party platform, demanding monetary reform, government ownership of railroads, and other reforms.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="135">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Municipal League?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote urban reform and efficient city government</option>
            <option letter="b">To support political machines</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce city services</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase corruption</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Municipal League worked to promote urban reform and efficient city government through research, education, and model legislation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="136">
        <prompt>What was the primary impact of the Columbian Exposition of 1893?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It showcased American progress and cultural achievement</option>
            <option letter="b">It promoted racial equality</option>
            <option letter="c">It criticized industrialization</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported labor unions</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Chicago World's Fair celebrated American progress and cultural achievements, though it largely excluded African Americans and presented a sanitized view of society.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
