<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="137">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the National Farmers' Alliance newspaper network?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To spread Alliance ideas and organize rural communities</option>
            <option letter="b">To support major newspapers</option>
            <option letter="c">To oppose reform movements</option>
            <option letter="d">To promote urban interests</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Alliance newspaper network spread reform ideas and helped organize rural communities, creating a communications system independent of mainstream media.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="138">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Atlanta Exposition Address?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It presented Booker T. Washington's accommodationist approach</option>
            <option letter="b">It demanded immediate equality</option>
            <option letter="c">It promoted political activism</option>
            <option letter="d">It opposed segregation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>Washington's Atlanta Exposition Address presented his accommodationist approach to race relations, emphasizing economic self-help over political and social equality.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="139">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Sherman Silver Purchase Act?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It failed to solve the currency problem and worsened the depression</option>
            <option letter="b">It stabilized the economy</option>
            <option letter="c">It helped silver miners</option>
            <option letter="d">It prevented the panic</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Sherman Silver Purchase Act failed to solve the currency problem and contributed to the Panic of 1893 by depleting government gold reserves.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="140">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Bureau of Immigration?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To regulate and restrict immigration</option>
            <option letter="b">To assist immigrants</option>
            <option letter="c">To promote immigration</option>
            <option letter="d">To provide citizenship</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Bureau of Immigration was established to regulate and restrict immigration, implementing new laws that excluded certain groups and established inspection procedures.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
