<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="141">
        <prompt>What was the main goal of the Catholic Total Abstinence Union?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To promote temperance within the Catholic community</option>
            <option letter="b">To oppose Protestant reform</option>
            <option letter="c">To support saloon culture</option>
            <option letter="d">To increase alcohol sales</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Catholic Total Abstinence Union worked to promote temperance within the Catholic community while countering anti-Catholic prejudice in the broader temperance movement.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="142">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the Northern Securities case?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It established the government's power to break up railroad monopolies</option>
            <option letter="b">It protected business combinations</option>
            <option letter="c">It reduced regulation</option>
            <option letter="d">It supported trusts</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Supreme Court's decision in Northern Securities Co. v. United States established the government's power to break up railroad monopolies under the Sherman Antitrust Act.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="143">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Cuban Reciprocity Treaty?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To maintain U.S. economic control over Cuba</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote Cuban independence</option>
            <option letter="c">To reduce trade barriers</option>
            <option letter="d">To protect Cuban industry</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Cuban Reciprocity Treaty maintained U.S. economic control over Cuba through preferential trade arrangements that made Cuba dependent on the U.S. market.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="144">
        <prompt>What was the primary effect of the Populist Party's fusion with Democrats?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It led to the decline of the independent Populist movement</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened both parties</option>
            <option letter="c">It achieved reform goals</option>
            <option letter="d">It united farmers</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Populists' fusion with Democrats in 1896 led to the decline of the independent Populist movement as it lost its distinctive identity and failed to achieve its goals.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
