<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
    <question number="153">
        <prompt>What was the main purpose of the Federal Elections Bill of 1890?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To protect African American voting rights in the South</option>
            <option letter="b">To restrict voting rights</option>
            <option letter="c">To eliminate polling places</option>
            <option letter="d">To support state control</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Federal Elections Bill attempted to protect African American voting rights through federal supervision of Southern elections, but failed to pass the Senate.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="154">
        <prompt>What was the significance of the National Farmers Alliance Exchange?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To create a cooperative system for buying and selling farm products</option>
            <option letter="b">To support large corporations</option>
            <option letter="c">To increase merchant profits</option>
            <option letter="d">To restrict trade</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The National Farmers Alliance Exchange attempted to create a cooperative system for farmers to buy supplies and sell crops, bypassing merchants and middlemen.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="155">
        <prompt>What was the main effect of the Supreme Court's E.C. Knight decision?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">It limited the government's ability to break up manufacturing monopolies</option>
            <option letter="b">It strengthened antitrust laws</option>
            <option letter="c">It protected small businesses</option>
            <option letter="d">It increased regulation</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The E.C. Knight decision limited the Sherman Antitrust Act by ruling that manufacturing was not interstate commerce, protecting manufacturing monopolies from federal regulation.</explanation>
    </question>
    <question number="156">
        <prompt>What was the primary purpose of the Chautauqua movement?</prompt>
        <options>
            <option letter="a">To provide adult education and cultural programs</option>
            <option letter="b">To promote political parties</option>
            <option letter="c">To support business interests</option>
            <option letter="d">To oppose reform movements</option>
        </options>
        <answer>a</answer>
        <explanation>The Chautauqua movement provided adult education and cultural programs to rural communities, helping to spread progressive ideas and cultural enrichment.</explanation>
    </question>
</quiz>
